My dream!
Year 1, Class 1, Kamogawa Asumi.
My dream is to become a rocket driver!
That's because I've heard that the Earth is very
pretty when you look at it from space.
So I want to become a rocket driver and go into space!
I want to take people to all sorts of different planets!
And when they're on my rocket...
my dad and Lion-san will get special free rides!
The end!
Even Underwater, There Is Space
I'm here at last!
This is my dream, the world of the moon.
Oumi-kun.
A24-21, Oumi Kei-kun.
Y-Yes.
Were you taking a nap standing up or something?
N-No, I'm sorry.
What is it?
Nothing.
What's up with her...
Now, type in your number using this keyboard.
Good, okay.
Next person!
Y-Yes.
A24-22, Kamogawa Asumi.
Are they even going to have a space suit that fits a 143 cm tall dummy?
What are you so depressed about, Asumi?
Today was just a size fitting, so don't worry about it.
The underwater zero-gravity exercise is later, right?
That's right, but...
Don't worry about it! They're special-ordering
one for you, after all.
We're just getting hand-me-downs from the government.
Yeah, but...
Don't just brood over it forever!
But, those two...
Even now, when I think about it...
How long are you guys gonna keep laughing about it?!
Sorry sorry.
eat a lot of different things...
Instead of always eating rice balls
...and get bigger by the time you go to space.
But I think it could be safer to be small.
Huh?
When you actually perform an EVA...
it's better to slightly lower the chances
of hitting meteoroids or debris.
I see...
Huh? What's a mete... metero-something?
Meteoroids and debris, Kei-chan.
objects in the void of space.
Meteoroids are very small celestial
which sometimes become meteorites.
And debris is what you call the trash-like stuff that people leave behind in space.
Starting with Sputnik which launched in 1957...
the upper half of the rockets used for launching satellites...
used-up satellites, broken pieces, paint fragments...
even gloves dropped by astronauts...
Large amounts of garbage are floating in space.
I see. There are garbage problems even in space.
I can understand meteorites being dangerous
but what's so dangerous about debris?
Debris flies around in all different directions
around the Earth at high speeds.
If you get hit by this debris during an EVA...
If you get hit?
Bang!
Cut it out, already!
Well, it just goes to show that there are all sorts
of dangers if we make it out into space.
Huh? What are we supposed to
do it something happens, then?
Asumi, don't ever leave me behind!
Yeah, of course.
Moron, it's space. We won't have
time to be looking after others.
I won't be asking you for help!
Well, if the time comes, well probably
only protect our highest priority.
But I hope I won't run away from those I have to
protect because of my fears and weaknesses.
So even impudent guys like you have their fears, huh?
Well, yeah.
What are they?
My eyebrows, I think.
Is that why you shaved them?
How would that be the reason?
Geez, we won't get to class on time!
It's mysterious.
I don't really like exercise...
but whenever I hear the word "pool"
somehow I always get excited!
Y-Yeah.
If we weren't wearing this, it would be the best...
Hey Kei-chan...
Can you pull up the zipper on the back?
Your back...
What are you doing, Asumi?
You put it on backward.
We're gonna be late, Asumi! Let's hurry!
Okay!
How unusual.
You're always smiling so much that it's sickening.
no matter what class you're in.
You think so?
I'm the same as usual.
meters wearing a flight suit and shoes.
For this training lesson, you will swim one hundred
Think of yourself as the only one you can depend on in space.
No matter what happens, don't trouble your teammates!
Keep in mind that this is training for
such a situation, so do it seriously.
Yes!
Damn that devil instructor!
because my form was a little off!
He didn't have to work me so hard just
If it's for your safety it's only natural.
I'd rather you train more,
instead of complaining so much.
Hey just what do you mean by that?
It means that I'd never want to go into space with you.
That's my line.
I'd rather die than go with you!
If anything happens Asumi will be there to save me!
Kamogawa-san, if you don't stop being
nice you'll eventually lose your life.
Sacrificing yourself for someone else is foolish.
to save a twisted person like you!
I'll tell you there's no one who'd want
Kei-chan!
I can protect myself on my own.
It really is irritating watching all of you.
Marika-chan!
I can understand what you're saying, but...
But, you can't go to space alone.
intoxicated with just getting in this school.
I don't want to be told that by someone who s
I'm not intoxicated...
Ukita Marika, right?
I've heard of her.
You sure know a lot when it comes to girls, you playboy.
Well, sure...
What's a playboy?
You don't need to know about that.
To tell you the truth, her father and
my grandfather know each other.
I've only heard her name before, but
I didn't think we'd be classmates.
I thought she was far older.
The one donating the most to this
school is her father, you know.
Wow, that's amazing!
Big deal, it's just a little donation.
Yeah.
But it was hundreds of millions of yen.
Hundreds of millions?!
You can't go to space alone.
You alone?
Hey hey girl!
Wanna go karaoke together?
It's all right! C'mon, let's go!
Don't touch me!
What the hell?
Stop putting on airs.
Hey you guys!
If you rough up a girl, I'll call the police.
What the hell? We just asked her out for karaoke.
Let's go.
Huh? Aren't you a Space School student?
I knew it!
because you were worried about Asumi!
You came to the dorm the day of the entrance ceremony
What are you doing at a place like this?
to be done with her part-time Job?
Ah, could you be waiting for Asumi-chan
See, over there? There she is!
be a little longer before she gets out.
She always works real late so I think it ll
Are you ready to order?
It's amazing that she can continue to work on top of school...
Ah, I give up...
What's wrong, Ooyama-sensei?
I special ordered a space suit for a
student that couldn't fit into one.
It seems like it will cost more money than I expected.
The government official's purse strings
are tight, so there's nothing I can do.
If that's it, it's simple.
Huh?
Well, let's go home!
I still have something to do, so...
Huh? You have work today, too?
Um, no, that's not it...
Well, whatever.
I'll go on ahead!
Yeah, see you tomorrow!
I hope I won't run away from those I have to protect because of my fears and weaknesses.
I wonder if I can do it as well, Lion-san...
Worried about her?
but the truth is she's scared of water.
Kamogawa's swimming like that
When she was small, she almost drowned in a river.
I think she's still pretty scared...
...so I'm not sure what's gotten in to her.
She's a stupid dummy that doesn't have any
common sense, and that can't be helped...
But don't bully her so much, okay?
it's not like I was bullying...
That dummy!
Trying so hard when she can't swim that well!
That is all for next month's budget distribution.
Space Astronaut Training Course
Space Astronaut
Staff Meeting
That is all for next month's budget distribution.
If you would kindly accept and cooperate...
What did you say?!
You can't be serious!
this unpleasantly high expense?
Wait, Ooyama-sensei, what is
suit that I mentioned before.
it is the price of the additional space
Additional?
Kamogawa Asumi, Mr. Principal.
This is about the student named
About the size being wrong.
Ah... but this expense for just one student...
Isn't there some way to cut the cost?
It is a suit that provides life support, so it's not so easily...
May I make a suggestion?
What is it, Sano-sensei?
Kamogawa Asumi leave the school.
I believe that it would be best to make
S-Sano-sensei!
What are you saying all of a sudden?
Kamogawa!
Back then, it would've been better
If I'd just had a little courage.
If I was still my weak self, I wouldn't have awoken to it.
little one, I'll tell you something interesting.
Something interesting?
Yes.
When you're in the water and you look ahead...
You can see the stars.
Marika-chan...
Hey hold on to this!
Really... you dummy...
Marika-chan, you came to save me.
I wonder if I would be able to save you, too?
I have to get much, much stronger, right?
I have to get stronger so I can
do more things without falling.
Here, dry yourself off.
Do you have a change of clothes?
Yes.
To begin with, this budget is within expected
boundaries, except in Kamogawa's case.
In this case, wouldn't having her leave be the best answer?
Don't say stupid things! There's no way we can do that!
It will become the responsibility of
the school that admitted her.
If we have her leave of her own accord,
there would be no problem, would there?
So that's what he meant by it being simple...
It is the first year for the astronaut course,
so we have a rather large number of students...
...but next year will only have ten students overall.
size of space suit will be needed.
In this case, it is unlikely that this
is the only one under 160 cm of height.
looking at our students now, Kamogawa
Her academic performance is only slightly above average.
Even it she continues training...
the chances of her distinguishing herself from the other
students and being able to go to space are exceedingly low.
To use this much money for such a student—
Wait a moment.
Are body size and grades that important for going to space?
That would be no different than the
training we've had up until now.
Having a student leave because of the school s
financial circumstances is out of the question!
Getting ordinary children to try and become
astronauts as a natural goal...
Having space be a more accessible thing
that is closer to people's lives...
Are these not what the Space School is trying to accomplish?
It's just as Shiomi-sensei says.
The budget will be very tight, but
it's for the future of this student.
Let us all cooperate and pull through this.
Shiomi-sensei.
Hm? Do you need something?
I heard that you pushed for the
admission of Kamogawa Asumi.
Why do you back that particular student so much?
It's her eyes.
She has the eyes that you've lost. That's all.
Since I was small, it's always been my
dream to become an astronaut.
My friends from long ago used to talk
about space with eyes like that...
Sano-sensei.
Try not to make things difficult. Just stay calm.
What you just said, about one's own accord...
Preview
Sano-sensei's words pierced my heart.
He said there's no way that I'd be
chosen to become an astronaut.
Why?
What does he mean, just because I m
Kamogawa Tomorou's daughter?
It even gets Kei-chan angry. I return to Yuigahama alone.
I don't know what to do anymore.
Next time on Twin Spica. Wounded Wings.