On a spring night, Virgo is spread out widely.
My favorite star, Spica, is this Alpha star.
If you stretch this line from the Great
Dipper, there's the North Star.
And if you pull the handle of the ladle...
there's the star of the cow herder, Arcturus, then Spica!
This line is called the Great Arc of Spring.
During the cherry blossom season, try looking for it in the south sky!
Preview
Hey, what's up there?
Group lists for the marathon practice the day after tomorrow.
Marathon?
It's that devil instructor again, huh?
But why do they have to take the
trouble of splitting us into groups?
Seems like we're going to split into two
groups and go there on a microbus.
They say it's training to run in actual outside terrain.
We take the trouble to go out and run till we drop again?!
Don't be happy about it, you dummy!
Let's see...
No way! I'm separate from Asumi!
Good things don't happen by being together with her.
Marathon Plan
B Co
Ukita Marika
Kamogawa Asumi
I'm with Marika-chan.
Asumi we may be separated, but we're friends forever, right?
Yeah.
You exaggerate too much all the time.
Of all the people, I had to be with Fucchii!
Fucchii?
Who's that?
Who? Isn't that what you're called?
Huh?
Shuu's always calling you that.
That guy...
Fucchii's a pretty good name, don't you think?
Yep.
They sure still are a noisy crowd.
You're not the one to decide, dummy.
You shouldn't take what Shuu says seriously...
Whether here or there, you're popular, little seagull.
Asumi says it's all right, so it's fine, don't you think?
Yeah.
I told you, don't decide for me.
Don't hit my Asumi, okay, Fucchii?
I told you, who said I was Fucchii?!
Huh? Asumi your name's up there too.
Huh?
Look...
Excuse me.
Sano-sensei...
U-Um, it said "summons" on the bulletin board...
I'm sorry for calling you all the way out here.
Huh? So you called me, Sano-sensei?
Let's talk someplace else.
Ah, Ooyama-sensei.
There's a summons out for Kamogawa Asumi,
but did anything happen?
Well, I don't know, but is something wrong?
No, I'm just worried about her.
Um, was it something I did?
Do you know the distance to space?
Huh?
Counting by time, it takes less than ten minutes.
A shuttle's orbit is at an altitude of at most 350 km.
Much closer than other foreign countries.
Yes...
But it doesn't mean that anyone can go.
Do you know why?
That is because the gravity gets in the way...
Wrong!
You cannot go to space unless you are chosen to do so.
Do you seriously think you can become an astronaut?
What do you mean?
Even if you work hard...
there is no way that you will be chosen
to become an astronaut.
Why are you suddenly telling me this?
Um, could I have been doing something wrong?
Umm... then I'll fix it, so...
Fix it? How?
I mean, that is...
Whatever you do, it's impossible.
That's because you are Kamogawa Tomorou's daughter.
Asumi's really late.
Hey Asumi!
You'll have to buy me an ice cream!
Geez, I waited for pretty long.
Asumi?
I-I brought you your bag, see?
Asumi...
Asumi-chan, are you there?
Would you like to have supper with me?
Is she at work?
Dad...
Dad, who had his head down everyday...
Dad, who always came home with a tired face...
Dad, who sometimes laughed sadly...
That was all because of that?
I don't want to go.
Even if I go, I can't do anything.
Even a person like you skips class, I see.
Next is your favorite class of astronomy right? Come on.
We're going.
It becomes like this...
Kamogawa-kun,
Asumi!
Kamogawa-kun, are you awake?
Stop daydreaming!
Y-Yes.
Therefore, take the distance between two stars and calculate...
Hey we're going to have zero-gravity training
in a jumbo jet in the fall, right?
That's what I've been looking forward to the most!
Do you know what the other name for that training is?
Asumi!
Oh, sorry, what were you talking about?
Nothing!
Asumi, you're acting weird!
What happened?
You can tell me anything!
I'm worried about you!
It something's bothering you, talk to me about it!
Talking might make things better!
Hey, what happened, Asumi?
I'm sorry for getting you worried, Kei-chan.
But I'm all right... really...
But...
It has nothing to do with you, so...
Idiot!
Even if you think you're troubled by yourself, that can hurt people!
You're the one who said we would all go to space together!
What do you mean it has nothing to do with me?!
We're friends because we can tell each other everything right?
What's up with you? Hiding in your own shell!
I hate you when you're gloomy!
Idiot!
What's wrong with her?
It's almost time to go!
Hurry and get on the bus!
Huh? That dummy's not with you today?
I don't know.
What? Did you have a fight with her or something?
Leave me alone.
Excuse me...
Have you seen Kamogawa-san?
She still hasn't come?
She isn't on the bus, even though it's time.
When I called the dorm, they said
she left in the morning as usual...
intention of going to school again.
Maybe Kamogawa-san has no
It's my fault...
It's because I said all that...
I hate you when you're gloomy!
Idiot!
Hey!
I'm going to look for her!
What's with her? Really...
Do you seriously think you can become an astronaut?
Even if you try hard, you won't be allowed to go.
That is because your...
Your father...
Your father was the one that caused the Shishigou to crash!
I can't ask Lion-san, can I?
If he was related to that accident or not...
If Dad was the cause of the Shishigou's crash.
For crying out loud, what are you guys doing?
All of you...
I don't know who wasn't there...
but it wouldn't be a good reason to skip the outside marathon.
Before worrying about others, worry about yourselves.
When you're listening to someone,
don't put your hands in your pockets!
Ow!
Well, well... isn't that enough, Nishida-sensei?
very practice has a make-up day right?
You sure are lenient toward the students, Sano-sensei.
I will contact Kamogawa's house for you.
None of you have to worry about it.
You all should go straight home for now.
Yes.
That teacher gives me a bad feeling...
I agree. That guy hit me with his fist!
Well, not that teacher...
That Sano-sensei...
Kamogawa-san that was missing?
How did he know that it was
Did he put the key somewhere else?
He told me about how he was a rocket engineer.
I never really heard a lot about Dad.
What if what Sano-sensei said was true?
What should I do?
Am I really not allowed to go to space?
Dad always forgets to check the mall.
There's one for me.
I wonder who it's from...
Suzunari-sensei!
Today?
Hey Lion-san!
You still can't forget Suzunari-sensei, right?
Huh? What's that?
You sure got something stylish there, kiddo.
Are you gonna a play a song for your lover over there?
It's good to be young.
You don't have to keep laughing at me because I'm off tune.
Someday I'm going to teach music at an elementary school!
Really? Me too!
That's my favorite song too!
Lion-san...
What is it, little one? I see you skipped school.
Lion-san, I...
If you don't hurry back, you'll mice the last train.
Well, Lion-san...
You're crying?
I'm sorry!
Lion-san, I'm sorry!
Why are you apologizing, little one?
It might have been Dad...
It might have been Dad who caused the Shishigou accident.
Little one...
been you standing next to Suzunari-sensei!
If that accident hadn't happened, it would have
I was prepared for it.
From the moment I became an astronaut.
it's nothing you have to worry about, little one.
No one actually knows the real cause of that accident.
Of course, it's not an accident that
happened because of one person.
But everyone who was part of Shishigou felt responsible for it.
Everyone's trying their best to regain what they have lost.
Your father is just one of those people.
You love the stars more than anything...
...and longed for space more than anyone else.
That's all you have to think about, little one.
The truth of the past isn't needed.
Your strong feelings are enough.
But you loved her right?
You've always, always loved sensei, right?
You can't even tell her your feelings anymore...
You can't tell her that you love her...
Little one, do you know what this song is?
It's called "Look up at the stars in the night."
It's a good song right?
It's the first song that I learned on this harmonica.
Really? Me too!
That's my favorite song too!
Yuuko-sensei, one more!
I'm taking it!
Sensei?
I can hear that song...
I think I'll try going to Tokyo as well...
Preview
Kasane-chan... that name is a memory that moves my heart.
Why can't people be honest?
The memory of hurting a friend still envelopes my feelings.
Please look at the stars when you're feeling sad, Kasane-chan!
Next time on Twin Spica: Our Star, The leaf Star.