Our Star, The Leaf Star
After the Shishigou crash that resulted in many casualties...
the JAMSF, the Japan Manned
Space Flight Bureau, and others...
have set up an accident research committee
on the tenth of the month.
They will actively research the cause of the accident...
...and allocate resources to compensate the victims of the crash...
Kamogawa.
Hmm?
You've been issued an order.
Accident Research Committee, bereaved family section?
Excuse me.
Shibata
Could you please leave?
But...
Every time I listen to it, it's the same thing.
My husband won't come back...
I can understand that.
But in our position of sincerity...
What do you mean, sincerity?!
If you are sincere, return this girl's body to the way it was!
But...
caused the accident that killed your father.
Kasane, this man works for the company that
They're responsible for your arm too.
solve this with just a little money!
They are bad people who are trying to
Kasane, show this man your arm.
Ma am...
No! I don't want to, Mama!
It's alright, just show it!
Show the bad experience you've had to go through!
Stop it No!
This is what you people did to this child!
S-Stop it...
Whoa, what's with your arm? Freaky!
You've got bandages, are you a mummy?
Sensei! I don't want to sit next to her!
She smells like medicine!
Hey! The mummy girl hit me!
Ow!
Quit it!
Hey stop it, Shibata-san!
Why do you keep doing violent things?
I'm exhausted, Kyoko.
That girl is the same age as Asumi.
Yeah... next year she'll be seven.
I'm the same as usual.
It's a bad job to settle people's lives with money.
I'm being hated and begrudged by the victims.
I've spent my life looking at the sky...
but after that accident, I've been bowing down my head.
It was just a dream.
After all it was nothing more than a dream.
a a om § mg o o...
I'll have to get rid of it next time.
All right, this is next!
There.
It's called a Swing by.
When we use the gravity of the Earth or
the Moon to slingshot to our destination.
If you're giving up with just this...
it'd be hard for you to become a rocket driver, little one!
Lion-san!
One more time!
What? How many times now?
Cadet Asumi!
Yes.
Today's training is now complete.
Then, Lion-san, I'll see you tomorrow!
Good grief...
It's finally over!
Laika!
Come here.
Laika.
Come here, I said!
What are you doing?
Idiot! Laika ran away!
What are you going to do about it?
You idiot!
Say something!
I'll go look!
Catch him properly!
Really...
Laika!
Where are you? Come out!
Geez, Laika, you...
I won't thank you.
You're the one who made Mm run wa .
Hey come with me for a bit.
I just found a really niee place.
Huh?
Hey, how far do you plan to go?
What are you going to do if we don't get back?
It's going to be your responsibility!
We're here.
It's amazing, right?
It's yellow wherever you look.
that cat fold we about it.
Hey whafs your name?
I'm Kamogawa Asumi
Shibata Kasane...
This is Laika.
He isn't attached to me so it's annoying sometimes, but...
Papa was fond of this cat.
Papa?
They say Papa died when I was one.
Because of the rocket crash.
This is it! My legs are stuck and I can't move!
Dear!
It's dangerous, please stand back!
Kasane!
Someone. Help this ehfld!
Hdp Kasane!
Papa would have been alive...
If that accident hadn't happened
and even my arm would be...
Kasanechan!
See! Stars!
They just fdl from the sky!
Are you an idiot?!
That's just an ordinary leaf
if is, but...
Hey Kasane chan, let's play again!
Well if $ okay.
Ah, so you're bi class two.
You were in the next class, but I didn't notice.
I haven't been to school for a while.
Of course you wouldn't notice.
Why? School is fun after all...
I hate that place.
There are lots of friends-there.
I don't need any friends.
Well...
If you want to be o*ie, then that would be ftwe.
Yeah! Let's be friends.
Hey Kasane-chan, what will you be when you grow up?
I don't really have any plans.
What about you?
I'm going to be a rocket driver.
Rocket?
YeaM lean go to many different stars.
Like you can become something like that.
I'd become one!
Then, I'll let you on the rocket!
Let's go to Spica together!
Spica?
Yeah, my favorite star, it's really pretty!
Asumi!
Pad!
Are you in -the middle of work?
Yeah.
I was piaybig together wtth Shibata Kasane ehan.
Shibata?
Kasane-chan...
Shibata
Is Kasane-chait here?
Cm sorry Kasane said that she didn't want to see you.
Shibata
Is Kasane-chait...
She's out right now.
She's at-the hospital today.
I see...
Really, what a persistent child.
They're certainly alike, parent and child.
Kasane* have you cleaned your room?
next week, so hurry and tidy up.
Well be living at trandpa's place starting
Mania, I won't be able to see my friends anymor ?
It can't be helped.
Hey Kasane-chan, let's piay again!
Hey, it's Shibata!
You're right!
What are you doing here when
you haven't been going to school?
Hey did you know? Her arm's really weird.
Really? What do ya mean?
Show it to us.
Stop it!
C'mon don't hide it from us!
Show it!
What are you dobigt! Stop it
Stop it! No!
No!
Hey let's go.
Y-yeah.
Hey wanna come over to my house?
Left play that game!
Yeah, let's go!
Kasaite-chan...
Hey Kasane-chan.
What is Hf ®o away.
Star...
be happy if you look at the star.
UoH San was saying that you ll
So, if you have this leaf, even your injury would...
Are you an idiot?!
What do you wean, Uon«aiif!
You think a bum would go away with a leaf?!
Eh?
Yoor papa...
Your papa killed my papa!
I don't want any money!
What I want is a kind papa and a beautiful body!
You have them!
You have all of them.
You aren't my friend!
•o way*
You just go away!
Kasane-chan.
You aren't the only one who's lonely.
Hub?
Who* there?
You aren't the only one who's lonely.
Shibata-san? She's not here.
1st Grade Class 2
She had moving preparations to do or something.
Moving?
near a famous hospital.
She's going to go live some place far away
She gave a goodbye speech at the farewell party yesterday.
Seems Mce die's leaving tomorrow.
You don't have to go eee Her off, little one?
She's leaving today right?
Pvt Kasanechan said we're not friends anymore.
Hey littleone
What people say isn't necessarily the truth.
No one can easily say what they fed
Saying that they are having fun when they are sad...
Saying that they are happy when they're spiteful.
Saying that they haft you when they Rice you...
Saying that they don't want to see you when they miss you...
The most important thing...
Yuigahama Station
is your heart little one.
Kasane, hurry and gef on.
Y-Yeah.
Awmichan!
Kasafie-eban.
Whew you feel sad, look at the star in the sky!
I'll look too! let's look at the same star!
because we're friends!
Here.
Asumi ehaiL...
I'm sorry, Asumi-chan.
What I really wanted wasn't Papa nor a beautiful body.
I wanted a real friend...
It's cleaned...
I who went baek to Space School...
Preview
.am trying to return to my former life
even with bad feelings toward Sano-sensei.
between Pad and Sanosewei long ago.
I won't think about what happened
between Pad and Sano-sensei long ago.
Because Kei-chan and everyone is supporting me.
And our promise.
Next time on Twin Spica: The Promised Five.
The Promised Five