On a spring night Virgo is spread out widely.
My favorite star, Spica, is this Alpha star.
If you stretch this line from the Pig
Pipper, there's the North Star.
And if you pull the handle of the ladle...
there's the star of the cow herder, Arcturus, that Spica!
ThU line is called the Great Arc of Spring.
During the cherry blossom season, try looking for it in the southern sky!
The Promised Five
Yob go back to school first thing tomorrow morning, right?
Y-Yeah.
Wed good night.
Pads stffl not back?
U he out drinking somewhere again?
I don't even have a key...
This is troublesome...
Maybe..
I knew it
I fed like a bvrgler...
Is it okay for Mm to be so careless?
Pvt Pad's ovt really late.
The late night shift? Guardsman?
Pad's working longer hours?
You won't find your dreams to Yuigahama.
Asumi your dream is my most important treasure.
Dad...
Everyone * trying their beet to regain what they have lost.
You seem all right now, little one.
Well then...
Perhaps I'll go too.
That dummy isn't here today either?
Whether or not you worry, that little seagull will show up soon.
Who said I was worried?
After aH her motives for coming to this school are
a Uttlc irregular just like someone else I know...
What is that supposed to wean?
Nothing.
More importantly Fuchuuya-kun, when are
you going to give up on that puzzle ring?
I D never give it to you!
Cheapskate.
U Kamogawa absent again today?
Hniph. There's ho helping that girl.
Now go to page 64, from the description of the Earth's orbit...
Asumi!
I'm sorry for being latd
Pont jost stand there, take your seat.
Yes.
Now then, imagine being on a rocket
that has successfully lifted off...
and is going around Earth.
At that moment, how would you find your current loeatton?
it must go around at a given speed...
Of course, to be at that height of the orbit
K.ei-cnan..
WWhat is H?
I made too many...
Huh?
Rice bails...
Fe quiet over there.
Y-Yw.
I'm s-wrry.
Therefore* in other words...
For crying out loud...
Really that dummy...
Good for you, Fuchuuya-kun.
What is?
That.
What happened with that certain student's ease, Sano-sensei?
Im sorry.
I see. Wei, it doesn't matter.
I wasn't expecting that much.
I heard.
You were a participant in that big mistake, weren't you?
It was thoughtless of me to ask you.
Unacceptable? What do you mean?
Weight-wise and cost-wise, ft's sufficient!
THU design is perfect. Whafs wrong with if?
there was someone who was against
the way you prioritized the cost.
Against it? Who?
It's Kamogawa Tomorou.
Kamogawa?
Hey hey. So, how is it?
It's another failure, Kamogawa!
Leave me alone.
You Just won't give up, huh?
He's the ehiefs favorite so...
Either way, this is the JAMSFs decision.
You won't be able to change it, no matter what.
Cease distribution if this title becomes licensed.
You there, don't slack!
You're behind in your laps, so youVe got two more to go!
And I thought I could hide ft fn all the commotion...
Pevfl!
Ah, Tm exhausted!
Just because it's an extra day for the practise we missed...
has our distance been lengthened?
fw sorry. Ncaose of we...
Don't apologize.
It was our ehoice to sldp it, so...
The distance is longer because of that devil instructor.
I thought I heard someone noisy... and it was Kei after all.
Even if we had wade an ewergeiicy landing
here* she wouldn't be any quieter.
Leave me alone!
Here.
Thank you, Fuchuuya-kun
Hmph, thank you very much.
You sure are talented.
angry Kke that comedian Hub?
You can probably laugh whfle you re
leant!
Kei-chan..
It's useless.
I'm so tired that I don't have
the strength to fight with Fucehii.
lot when I think about ft...
Ever sbiee we got into this school
all our training has just been running.
Are we really going to be able to go to space like this?
Who knows.
Thafs the hard part about newly-implemented courses.
There's no tradition or instruction manual
We're fumbling our way through this, and «o is the school.
That's my share.
Gonna drink any?
I don't need it.
OK ready?
Then drink mine.
I haven't pvt my mouth on it or anything.
I'm not thirsty.
Even I'm getting tired.
How long is this basic training going to last?
Surely some people will leave the school because of all this...
Surpistagly that might be the school's reasoning.
Hey Asumi promise me something?
Huh?
That you won't leave school untfl we
reach our graduation ceremony.
At least, for us here right now...
No matter what bad times there will be.
let's promise that we won't give up!
Kei-chan-
Fucchii too...
There.
What are you doing?
What do you wean, "What?"
We're putting our hands together!
Huh? Our hands?
Yeah, c'imoh!
I can't do this!
Uu, stop with the complaining and just do if
I don't want anyone here to give up!
AH right ad right.
Of course, Kei-chan too.
Of course!
Asumi?
Sorry, couM you watt a Mf?
Asumi!
How far did Asumi go off to?
Hey let's go baek. I'm hungry.
It's fine to leave that dummy behind, so...
WcH weH saying what you don't really wean.
Hey what is if?
Hurry hurry!
Hey!
Kei-chan, sorry to keep you waiting.
Y-Yeah.
Here.
WdL then
Really... dummy.
Hey Marika chaH, let's do it.
let's promise.
We're going to promise not to
give up and graduate together.
L sueh a thing...
4wt do ft wrth us.
Or it won't end.
you wherever you go and bring you back.
Even if you get away how, this dummy will ehase
I don't want to have to get involved with that.
Just think of it as being destined to be together.
But...
It's a promise.
I promise.
L promise.
Yeah!
Hey Asumi can I ask you something?
nmw,
Well... did something happen with Sano-senseif
You know, Asumi you got summoned, right?
YooVe been absent-minded since then.
who sumnioiied you that time.
I thought it might have been Sano-sensei
That time, you came to class late.
Something felt weird about you too.
So I thought, maybe...
Kei-chan, 1 got a little homesick.
It was my own problem, and I exaggerated it by myself...
It's not like something happened with a teacher.
She's hiding something, after all.
Am I that unreliable?
At that extra practice just now...
Thank you, Kei-chan.
I was happy.
I was ready happy.
Asumi*
You can't always eat just rice balls!
I'll treat you!
IH treat you to something really tasty!
KKKei Chan
C'mon, c'mon! Let's go!
live we a ride sometime, Fuchuuya-kun.
1,000 yen
Oh my... can't you let that go in the name of friendship?
What friendship is that?
How cold.
Hurry and get on.
More I change my mind.
That* why I like you, Fuchuuya-kun
Idiot!
My you even have another helmet ready.
At this rate, wouldn't it be faster if we walked?
Pe quiet. If you have a problem get off.
Well I was it)iiddng how FuchiMike it is
the way it just goes at its own pace.
So Nee his owner.
Whaf* that?
You sure are a weird guy.
Ami you're the one that's at Ms own paee.
Pretty much.
Really...
Such a good kid.
Kei and the little seagull as well.
The type that destroy themselves because they're so good.
Of course, you're a good Idd too, FuecML
I don't need to hear that idiot.
thank you.
You're living in a place (flee iNs by yourself?
Pretty tnovh.
This is even wore erode than Kamogawa* place.
He's the son of a politician, so I thought
he could afford a better place.
Are you that sorry to part with me?
Her surname's a bit unusual too.
OK you read that as "Vktta."
Uktta?
Yeah.
I see...
Aritsune Jun ichirou
Ukita Marika
Urakawa Kenji
NOTE: Lion-san is reading out the symbols of Ukita's name.
A lot of happiness in spacei" huh?
A fitting name for an astronaut.
She's a really pretty girt and she tries her best.
I see...
Is she your friend, little one?
Yep!
I see.
Lion-san?
I'm relieved.
Huh?
you'd rarely talk about your friends.
When you were stffl in Yuigahama
At your age if way be hard to realize, but...
dream as you is truly wonderful
Having friends that share the same
Pid you have friends like that?
Yes.
I haven't seen them in a while.
I wonder how they're doing.
I wonder what Lion-san's friends are like.
Unlike Lion-san, they would age.
So they wight be old men now.
Old men?
Don't say stuff like that!
What's she getting hyped op about herself?
Asumlehans talking to herself more these days.
Though she was a bit strange before..
Maybe she's tired from not being used to living by herself.
Pvt, Lion-san..
It doesn't change that fact that you're my first friend.
Thank you for coming to Tokyo.
Starting today I'll be going to school wrtti Lion-san.
Preview
Starting today I'll be going to school with Uoti dait
And Sano-sensd finally lashes out viciously at Kei-chan.
tot what I saw in the library...
was the figure of Sano-sensei smiling
peacefully at a space photo album.
Semei has been looking't the same
thing we have all this time, right?
Next time on Twin Spica: A Sad Smile.