On a spring night, Virgo is spread out widely.
My favorite star Spica, is this Alpha star.
If you stretch this line from the Big
Pipper, there's the North Star.
And if you pufl the handle of the ladle...
there's the star of the cow herder, Areforus, then Spica!
This line is called the Great Are of Spring.
Pining the cherry blossom season
try looking fortij; in the southern sky!
A S9tl Smil .
For the Astronaut Training Course, we're al together for Ft...
I have different classes than the others.
but everyone can choose their own subjects, so sometimes
In any ease, this sure is a large school.
Isn't Hf (retting around is a little tough.
Hey look lion-satt!
It's Fuchuuya, the annoying brat!
Morning!
Morning...
That's Kei-chan and Suzuki-kun.
What's with that guy? He doesn't have eyebrows.
OK and -that's Marika-chan over there.
Ah, lion-sans intrigued by her!
P Pon't be ridiculous.
H... h-hey...
Sano-sensei!
Hm? What do you need?
Weil...
Hurry awl go to the classroom. Class will start soon.
Sawo-sensel!
Pid you say something to Asumi... I mean, to Kamogawa-san?
Kamogawa-san has been acting weird lately, so...
you fed guilty about something?
Since you're not responding, does that mean
Since you're not responding, does that wean
Why are you coming to we about Kawogawa in the first place?
PM Kamogawa say something?
Asumi won't say anything.
Asumi isn't the kind of person who teds on people!
She keeps everything inside, no waiter what people say to hoi
That's why I'm worried!
What's Kei yelling about?
Something about the little seagull perhaps...
Really they all go on about Kamogawa, Kamogawa...
Then 1 will respond.
It's flue to worry about your friend.
Put instead of worrying about other people, why don t
you worry about getting them out of the way?
Huh?
There aren't enough seats to allow everyone
to be friends and become astronauts.
If there was Just owe seat left, would you let Kamogawa take it?
With the other courses, even if you don t
proceed into the space program...
you can receive other qualifications, and it's advantageous
for employment and further education.
That's also one reason why so many people apply for this school.
there's not much value if you don't go through with it.
Oh the other hand, with the Astronaut Training Course
I knew that from the beginning.
No one believes that everyone can goto space.
And that Sano guy...
Someone believes.
Huh? Wbatf
There S one person who believes that everyone can go to space.
There's no mistaking it. It's that girl.
Uotisan.
Are you worried about what that teacher said, IHUe one?
It's true that by looking at the cost of training, and
the number of rockets that are to be launched...
ft will b€ impossible for everyone lo
go to space before they graduate.
John Mem* was 71 years old on his second space flight.
NOTE: Actually, John Glenn was 77 years old when he flew on the space shuttle Discovery in 1998.
Huh?
In 1961 he became the first American astronaut
to orbit the Earth as part of Project Mercury.
You knew that as wed right, little one?
Yeah.
birthday on the International Space latkwu
Last year, a Russian cosmonaut celebrated Ms
What was his name again?
Hi was pretty oM as well.
However old you are, there is still a chance to go into space.
With you and everyone else being so young.
there are still many opportunities.
lion-tan, I...
Km?
I'm going to go find a book on the history of space at the library!
I K definitely be able to go with everyone, right?
There don't seem -to be a lot of people.
I wonder where KeNhan went...
If you're wondering about Oumi-san I saw her at the cafeteria.
She's probably planning to strike.
Strike?
Just leave it alone.
Well there are times when you just want a day to rest.
But...
Now then, page SO in your textbook.
When you go out to space in a rocket...
different forces act on the rocket
than upon your return to Earth...
.after taking off vertically the shuttle turns
horizontally to order to gain speed.
On the other hand, when -the spacecraft're enters
the atmosphere upon returning to Earth...
we use that resistance provided by
the atmosphere to oor advantage.
lower -the speed without expending fuel...
The resistance in the atmosphere helps to
lower the speed without expending fuel...
This is troubiesowe, Saiw-semei!
There are complaints from the students' parents as wed!
Getting them out of the way..."
And worse, this is at a time when people are
complaining about the strength training!
Please don't say things to lower the
students' motivations any further!
Even if you say that it's a fact that there
are students boycotting your class.
Something is wrong with your attitude these days!
There are even rumors going on about you between the teachers.
The head teacher is planning disciplinary action..
There is no need for that.
I've already submitted my resignation.
S-Sano-sensei! I didn't wean to have you go that far...
Po yov have a btf?
I was wondering why you had such a problem with Kamogawa...
I felt bad, but I looked into ft a bit.
You were in the JAMSF Shishigou Pevdopment Team, right?
Weren't you and Kamogawa's father there at the same time?
That really was an unfortunate accident.
That was not Just an accident, it was a willful disaster!
It is true that Kamogawa Tomorou
and I were there at the same time.
Put my work was scrapped because He wanted safety first!
My design that I had worked on for years...
Just because he was liked by the team leader...
He had ho right*
And then that happened!
Pecades after that accident, at every
opportunity people would say...
So, you were part of the death team?
Even though I was taken off the team and couldn't do anything...
I heard.
You were a participant in that Mg mistake, weren't you?
It was thoughtless of me to ask you.
I won't ask you for anything again.
Everywhere I go, that abominable incident follows me.
You said you chose Kamogawa Asumi
because of her eyes, didn't you?
Those eyes... what was it abovt those eyes?!
I was also...!
I was also...
If that wan hadn't taken everything away from me...
I think that's enough misguided resentment.
What?!
You didn't know?
Right after you were dropped from the team...
Kamogawa Tomorou was dropped from
the Shishigou Pevefopmettt Team as wefl.
T-That can't be possible...
I don't really know the details myself
but I heard an unsettling rumor.
Rumor?
As soon as Kamogawa was dropped from -the team...
the budget for the Shishigou was drastically reduced.
What did you say?!
Also...
wasn't actually wade entirely within this country.
The Shishigou, famous for being alNapanese...
The reason behind Hie aeeident isstflla state secret, though.
(rood morning, Marika-chan.
Umm, where's Kei-chan?
She was here.
Put instead of entering the campus, she
wade a U-turn and ran off somewhere.
but it because first period is Saito-sensei?
Hey!
Shi went that way!
Okay!
Realty... we always have to take care of that dummy!
(rood work.
Found you, Kei-chan!
Class is going to start!
Let's go.
No.
You didn't go to Space Physics yesterday either, right?
If you drop this credit, we cant graduate together!
I don't ever want to take lessons from Sano-sensei.
Put...
You were told all that, but you don't fed anything?
I didn't think he was a teacher that would say those things!
Whafs wrong with earing for your friends?
I don't want to be a person who can't treasure her friends!
Kei-chan...
You couldn't say anything back to that though.
Marika-eban...
I know.
I'm pathetic because I couldn't say anything back!
But it's frustrating!
It wouldn't be too late to tell Mm now.
I don't want to go because I can't think of what to say!
You don't have to say anything back.
Let's Just go to class, okay. Kei-chan?
So are you cowing to class, or not?
Come on, it's going to start!
OK find
I get Hi You want me to go to class, right?
For crying out loud, why did it turn out this way...
She's got such a happy face.
The little seagull's smile sure is cute.
How could that stupid look...
Trying too hard...
Panmiit, everyone around here..
Here be comes...
I'll be teaching this for a while, starting today.
My name is ShiornL Nice to meet you all.
What's going on?
Umm senseK
What is M
Pld SanO sensei... well...
Sano sensei has decided to leave the school
for a while; for his own reasons.
What? Poes that wean he qutt?
WdL to pvt it simply yes.
Hey hey
listen to me.
There is one thing I'd like to get out of the way to begin with.
the Astronaut Training Course has just been established
so explanations may have been lacking...
up to shape, so I apologize for this.
mi facilities might not have been
It is also a fact that very few people will probably be able to go.
Put I don't want you to be pessimistic about this.
In the near future, the use for astronauts will surely increase.
from this school will put you at an advantage.
When that time comes, the fast that you have graduated
Many thwgs way happen, bvt no matter
what sort of situation you are put in...
Many thugs way happen, but no waiter
.do not throw away your vision and dreams of
going to space untfl the end and so your best.
TMs is what the teaching staff wishes from their hearts.
Now, we witl proceed with the lesson.
Now, we wffl proceed with the lesson.
Put stid I wonder why he suddenly decided to quit.
He wouldn't quit over just that.
Something else important most have happened.
What is this "something?"
Who knows?
Who cares what it is? Its probably something stupid anyway.
no idea what he was thinking.
Those eyes were scary anyway. I had
That's right, and plus, listen to this.
What is (tf
That teacher said that Asumi...
Professor's Room
Sano
Sano-sensei!
It's the same, isn't it?
Sewsei, it's the same for you is* f?
You were looking at the same thing, right?
There certainly was a time like that for me.
Pvt before I knew ft, I couldn't see it anymore
Don't lose sight of it!
Why is it?
Why do adirits have those sad expressions?
Even Suzunari setud.. wen Uonmn...
Even Pad...
Even Sano semei...
If only everyone could go into space..
Semel I'm fore you'll be able to see ft!
You'd be able to see it again!
Surely...
Preview
We don't know anything about Marika-chan's early life.
I end up making Marikaehan angry.
Suzuki-kun cheers we up nonchalantly.
My past is connected to the Shishigou accident...
be able to understand each other much, much better soon.
Many things have happened, but I believe that everyone will
then, one day, Marika-chan feinted.
Next time on twin Spica: Alone.
Next time on Twin Spica: Alone.
Alone