On a spring night. Virgo is spread out widely.
My favorite star Spica, is this Alpha star.
If you stretch this line from the Mg
Pipper, there's the North Star.
And if you pad the handle of the ladle...
there * the star of the cow herder, Arcturus, then Spica!
This line is called the Great Are of Spring.
Paring the cherry blossom season
try looking for ft in the southern skyi
Alone
I'm finished.
1$ that all?
been taking your medicine lately.
Marika, it seems you haven t
take your medicine property*
You don't have a normal body!
I'm going on ahead now!
The real Marika never had a rebellious attitude like that...
1 was always atone.
I am always alone.
Well Miss...
the train has already made one full eircutt.
Let us burry and move on.
Wrect sunlight will be bad for your health.
At long last, this is the first outing
your father has allowed $inee you were bom, so...
Tdl me without reservation, wherever it is.
Here, Miss, what about this place?
The Toritsu Zoo... or would you like the aquarium?
Thaf* why I -thought N be alone from here on as wel.
I thought I would be all right with that.
I don't need any friends.
Miss?
Marika-chan!
Can I have a second?
W... what is it?
was finished in Chiba.
Weft, you know, a new Space Observation Center
Yes, where Japan's largest observatory is, right?
OK come now.
I just read it in the papers.
From the perspective of someone who didn't read it
that sounded Just a tad spiteful.
Don't be Jealous.
I'm not jealous!
And, well we all decided to go to
the Space Observation Center together.
And we thought, "What about Marikachan as welLT
I'm sorry, but I'll seelitte.
Eh? Pvt ft's dose, so the transportation fare would be cheap...
.and there's a discount on admission
to the observatory for Space School students...
It won't cost a lot of money...
I've told you before. I hate friendly behavior like that.
Marikachan!
Hey watti
let go!
Im sorry.
Every person has their own concerns.
ID say it directly, Kamogawa-san. You're a nuisance.
Marikachan!
leave her alotie, Asumi
Put...
That's why I told you it's useless to invite her.
Even when we call her over at lunch
she never comes.
She most really like being alone
Poesn't she get lonely?
Asumi...
I don't need any friends.
I forgot the meaning of loneliness long ago.
That's what I've always believed.
That's why...
I'll be leaving now!
ID say ft directly, Kamogawa-san. You're a nuisanee!
Uttie seaguffl
buzuki kun.
Hey.
Those clothe*... a part-time Job?
Yeah
a moment of relaxation to an exhausted city.
I have the important Job of providing
I don't get much in return, though.
I see...
ty the way, "little seagull" was...?
Don't worry about it.
Hey
The vending machine over there's the last one.
so can you wait a bit?
When Tin done, let's go on a date.
Huh?
ly "date", you wean here?
Yeah.
Emergency Exit
Uttte seagull!
This way.
I guess this year if'd be hi this direction
Hmnt, let's see-.
There it is.
Here.
It's Saturn!
you can see it quite clearly huh?
Even though Wt an older model
Yeah, I can seethe rings perfectly!
Pan, Alias, Prometheus, Pandora...
Epimetheut, Janos, Mimas..
The moons of Saturn!
long ago, I used to recite them by heart like this.
Enceladus, Tethys...
Tdesto Calypso, Pione> Helene...
Rhea, Titan, Hyperion, lapetus, Phoebe.
Suzuki-kun, do you eowe here a lot?
Pretty much.
It's all right to walk into places Mce this?
If* all right. This is my dad's building, after all.
Huh?
Why don't you sit down, little seagull?
tot it really is mysterious.
Pespite (Ming able to see all these stars...
ft's possible that not one star is really there anymore.
What is there is distant light
that's tens of thousands of years old.
In other words, we're looking at phantom light.
Put ffs like FueeM said.
Huh?
You'll be smiling as long as you see the stars.
Suzuki-kun.
Thank you.
For what?
Nothing...
finback!
Welcome home.
Oh, he said to eat that.
Si* that Idd with the black-rimmed glasses
came and left those here
Seems Mce he went out of his way to
boy it from the fruit shop on the comer.
Ah, and there were a lot of calls from Kei-chan.
Has something happened between you guys?
No...
Hey why are yoo crying?
PM I say something I shouldn't hav ?
Huh?
I won't allow it!
WM
You don't even understand why?
Marika!
Marika, open this door right now!
You're different from normal people!
If you go that far, ami something happens, what will yoo do?
I'm a normal person!
the real Marika wouldn't say such things!
What's this "real Marflca"?
rmwysdfi
Marika!
I won't fed lonely.
I can live by myself.
At least, that's how it was supposed to be.
Put turn..
It's a promise.
L.. promise.
YeaW
I see, Fueehfs name is Shinnosuke?
Don't look without asking.
It's all right, isn't tt? It's a compliment.
I was thinking it wasn't really a suitable name for you.
How's that supposed to be a compliment?
after your great-grandfather, right?
Fuchuuya-kun, you were named
Great-grandfather?
Yeah, he was a skilled fireworks craftsman.
I see, Fucchi comes from a famfly of fireworks craftsmen.
instead of following in their footsteps.
And here you are taking the Astronaut Training Course
Quiet. I'm going to launch a huge firework right into space.
Hey what about your name, Kei-chan?
Poes it have to do with
your family making Japanese sweets?
Noway.
I'm told my grandmother took a character
from the name of a vocalist in a band she liked.
Keisuke" if it was a boy. "Kei" if it was a girl.
I see...
What about you, Asumi?
Me?
My mother gave me my name.
She said it would let me become someone who
can look forward to tomorrow, no waiter the situation.
NOTE: The kanji for Asumi's name is 明日: tomorrow and 見: look at.
I see. it suits you, it seems.
Pvt my father's name is Tomormi
and my mother's name is K oko.
NOTE: Tomorou = 友朗: cheerful companion,
Kyoko = 今日子: today's child.
So don't you think it's strange that I'm named Asumi?
NOTE: Strange in the sense that her name
doesn't relate to her parents' names.
It's really alee.
It seems like she thought really hard about your name.
Yeah. They seem to be a happy family.
You think so?
It's true that...
You're different from normal people!
The real Marika wouldn't say such things.
Would yoo stop HA
Marika-chan?
What is ft afl of a sudden?
Marika-chan, mm...
Pont eonte elosd
Don't come pestering into everything like that!
You the one who's always being sheltered!
What?
Marfkaehan! Wait a minute!
Marika-chan...
That is all for today.
Ah, I didn't understand anything today either.
Somehow, I'm depressed...
Eating a delicious lunch should help at a time like this.
That* true! Yoo say such nice things, Shoo.
Asumi left go!
If we don't hurry, the cafeteria'll get crowded!
Y-Yeah!
I wonder what today's lunch will be...
Martka ehan didn't even come back to class...
You sore are reading something difficult.
I'm, you're interested in cytology?
Cytology
I see, you're interested in cytology?
It has nothing to do wtth you.
Nothing to do wtth in* huh?
That's true. She's also a real meddler.
But it's not like she's been sheltered.
Well it's true that her father is a good wan.
But everyone Has their own concerns.
Were all different, right?
I don't want to listen to a lecture.
If I said she and I were both bom in Yuigahama,
would you understand a little better?
All-Japanese Manned Space Rocket Fails to Launch
List of casualties (Unordered)
Kamogawa Kyoko Critical
Yuigahama
Search Keyword / Kamogawa Kyoko
Kamogawa Kyoko
been in a coma for five yean.."
Kamogawa Kyoto sati, who had
oh the fifth day of her Sfrd year."
has died without regaining consciousness
on the fifth day of her 33rd year."
on the fifth day of her 33ri year.'
After that, the same. "
Don't drop your paed
Yeah, yeah.
Geez, when are we going to be relieved from this agonizing hell?
AD right!
Now we can be released from hell!
AO right, all of you finish up!
Marika-cban?
It's painful..
Miss...
It has become a downpour.
it is a pity but let us go home.
I wHI get the car ready right away.
If* me. Please bring the ear around.
There was no plaee I ready wanted to go.
I just... wanted to run away.
Marikaehait!
I wanted to run away from that place.
To a faraway place., farthest from there.
To a faraway place..
No matter how much my legs hurt...
No matter how much my breath became short...
Even if no one notieed...
Even if I was alone..
Pvt really...
the place I really wanted to go was...
What I really wanted was...
Oh my you've woken up?
let's see..
Vo you fed any pain anywhere?
Po yoo fed sick?
It seems like a light anemia.
I see. Wei there's nothing to worry about
Have you been eating property?
You shouldn't miss meals for the sake of dieting.
The course you gtrls are in
is basically a test of physical strength.
Is it all right to go how ?
I suppose. It eareful.
Oh, that's right.
A few girls have been anxiously waiting outside for a whHe~
Friends of yours?
to go home*" many times, but they wouldn't listen.
I told them "She's stfl sleeping, and it's late.
so go home," many times, but they wouldn't listen.
I told them, "She's stfl sleeping, and it's late.
I told them, "She's stfl sleeping, and tfs lat*
Kids around your age are lucky.
Your feelings for others are so pure and straightforward.
With me, I have to have a reason to worry about someone.
Come in, come in.
I K go get some tea ready
so yoo can go ahead to my room upstairs.
Ah, IV help!
A storage room?
Who't tber ?
My imagination?
Pvt it's mysterious...
When I'm here, I fed calm There's a nostalgic smefl.
I wonder where Marika-chan went...
Geez, she's annoying.
Kei-chan
Good morning, Kei-chan.
Ah, morning.
I'm sleepy again today.
I hope I don't fall asleep doling class...
Ah, Marfcachan, good morning!
Thank you for everything yesterday.
That surprised me~.
Waft, Marika-chaw!
Ah... hey, wait up!
Ah.
I wonder what kind of guy the Mttie seagull Nkes.
What is it all of a sudden? You like that kind of girl?
Pad taste.
You sure aren't honest.
Here.
Hey you ■
In middle school it seemed like she Heed someone.
He died from an illness.
You're no match for someone who died...
Yeah?
Preview
He was the first person that I talked with about space.
First love? If that was my first love...
heart-breaking time of my life.
then it would be the second most
Who decided that spring is the most beautiful season?
same cherry blossoms don't bloom twice.
Even -Though spring comes every year, the
Even though spring comes every year, the
Even -though spring comes every year, the
same cherry blossoms don't bloom twice.
Next time on Twin Spica. Asumi's Cherry Blossom.
Asumi's Cherry Blossom