Our country's first manned exploratory
space rocket, the Lion, was launched.
However, 72 seconds after liftoff...
The liquid fuel booster suddenly exploded...
And although the Space Control Center activated what could be called its self-destruct system...
...the flight suspension system did not function correctly...
The Lion fed into an urban area and caused a
huge disaster with many civilian casualties.
Eleven years later...
Asumi's Cherry Blossom
For becoming a rocket driver, physical fitness is even
wore important than knowledge or engineering!
Jogging everyday is fundamental.
Wbafs wrong, little one?
Just HOW...
It seemed like someone was watching.
Now then, the answer to question five is...
Kamogawa. Kamogawa?
Kamogawa Asumi.
How many limes do I have to eall you hm?
I'm sorry.
Why are you always just gazing at the sky*
It wasn't the sky.
I was looking at space.
Space?
Fine, then. Look at space, or whatever
it is, as much as you want.
Yuigahama Middle School
I heard...
Huh?
I heard that childhood friend of yours ready is an idiot.
Hey wait op!
Hey Fuchuuya!
There's a rumor floating around school...
.about the essay she read out loud during Japanese class.
She said 1 have a ghost friend who wed to
be an astronaut." I heard she was serious.
She's already in middle school.
is there something wrong with her*
You know...
If you hang around her, you'll become an idiot too.
Ow...
What are you doing?
OK looks like you bumped into my leg.
Idiot!
Sorry about that.
Pawn Hi I'd remember this!
Who* that?
I fed like I've seen him before, but...
For becoming a rocket driver, physical fitness is certainly
more important than knowledge or engineering!
I irt doesn't it seem like this paee is way faster than usual9
1 give op!
Oo	on alone, little one!
Okay! I'll wait for you up ahead.
Hey!
Huh?
I'm Shimazu Takas W.
I	know. You're Kamogawa Asumi right?
Y-Yeah...
Waft there for Just a second.
Yuigahama C
Here, have this.
To Space: The Human Race Stands on Earth
Utagawa Keigo
This... Whaf's this for*
I went to Yuigahama Elementary School too.
Huh?
I was absent a lot, so you might not remember me.
Remember th« essay presentation in the gym?
My dream is to become a rocket driver!
I knew that you were interested bi space.
Besides, I don't need this book anymore.
What do you wean, you don't need it...
For now, this is enough for me.
I've been sketching every day.
Even though ft's Just scribbling.
I tee...
fey hA not wrth yoo today?
Who?
The ghost of the astronaut.
Huh? Umm...
You ean see him?
Noway!
Pot you really are amazing.
You car see something that no one else can.
Hey TakashH
What are you doing over there?
It's time for your examination!
Oh man.
That lady is pretty scary when she gets angry.
Wdt see you later.
Thank you for the book!
So you were watting for m& Wile one..
let's go, UoH San!
Yeah...
H-Hey, little one!
PM something good happen?
Hey Asumi finished yet*
Yes!
M
Around this area, I can't keep up with her at affi
She always quickens her pace when she gets here...
So that was it.
Hey what are you always drawing here?
Huh?
Nab, ft's not really something I can show off.
Really? I want to sed
OH, well I was... I was drawing that.
That cherry blossom free in the park on top of that hffl
I really want to draw the cherry blossoms in full bloom.
but that tree's flowers don't bloom.
Why?
it 9 iriB ufiiy wi«iy inuwffii use iriai uiun i
bum down during the lion accident, but...
Since that accident, no matter how many
years pass or how many springs come-.
for some reason, ho flowers will blossom anymore.
So my drawing is stffl incomplete.
When those cherry blossoms bloom. I'll show you my drawing.
Okay.
Pot doesn't that wean you won't show it to we for a long tiwe
Huh? What*
You've got a pretty sharp wit, Kamogawa!
I always thought your specialty was being absent-minded.
Thaf's mean! I'm wot absent-minded!
Wow! Shtoiazu kwi, you're really good!
You can really fell it's a space shuttle!
Of course. You're waking a big deal oot of it.
Hey you promised, right7 Let me see your drawing, too.
Mine is..
fim f
Nr ther not show yoo, afiir at
Hey let's stop by the areade!
Let's go! What about you, Fuchuuya?
I'm Hot going to that waste of time.
It's ad right, bu't Hf
It's ad right. Isn't lit
Pot yooll laugh!
I promise I won't laugh!
What should I do...
Hey isn't that Kamogawa and Shimazu from class E?
What7 They're going oof?
We gotta tell everyone!
Let me borrow your cell phone! Cefl phone!
Surd
Huh? Fuchuuya?
Where are you going?
The arcade.
Hey you laughed after affi
Sorry about that.
Put ft's just like you Kamog wa.
Huh?
It'd be great if you could become one. A roeket driver.
YouVe already read the entire book from before?
Yeah, it was really interesting.
Thai 11 bring you something else later.
Thank you!
You know what?
I in reaHv afaw
to the planetarium with you.
IlN.
Thank you for visiting our planetarium today.
We wffl how introduce you to the world of the spring sky.
about astronauts, Shimazu-km
You certainly have a lot of books
I suppose.
Hey look over there.
Hmmf
The hospital's second floor window.
When I was little I was always a patient there
I couldn't wove much, and the only things I could see
from that window were the sky and the stars.
More I knew it, I got interested in space.
How far don space stretch ootf
b there an end to space
If there is, what lies beyond?
I wanted answers to those questions
so I read as many books about it as I could.
I see...
Put, the answers don't really exist anywhere.
but ffs probably impossible.
My dream was to go and see for myself
Don't say that.
Why do you say ffs impossible?
(HI be over toon...
my life.
It's Just a joke! Ajokd
I thought you'd notice it with your sharp wit again.
I'm just saying that Tim not very smart.
Well see you.
You can go!
You can definitely go!
Since I'll be driving the rocket!
lei's go together. To space.
Thanks. If you're driving, I might be able to go.
Together, boh?
Hey!
Heyi Are you all right?
feta hold of yourself, Idd!
It's wot like be'd be able to bear me..
I gotta eal the little one...
I'm fine.
Huh?
It'll settle down quickly
I'm used to it.
Don't fed me, you can
I'm fine.
Kamogawa, aren't you on duty today?
You should at least make sure you clean
the blackboard before class starts.
Yeah...
Hey why would they do something like that?
I'm causing Mm IrouNe, too.
It seems that by being with Shimazu-kuti
Kamogawa.
Hmw?
You haven't come around lately. Has something happened?
Yeah, I guess...
I still have wore books about space.
I still have some books about space, so eome to my room," huh?
What are you going to do when you puli her into your room?
You!
Ow!
What are you getting all serious about, Shtoiazu?!
Owl let go!
I said let go!
PamntH! Po you want to die?!
I don't need any books anymore.
Thai's enough...
I don't have anything to do with Shiwazu-ktw
Hey Uott san
Why did I say something lilee that?
IV® been acting strange these days.
I don't really know myself.
I wonder why...
Wbafs wrong, Asumi?
Aren't you going to school?
I don't want to go today.
I Ml
Make sure you go tomorrow.
Yeah...
Kamogawa!
Look, listen to me calmly.
Shimazu... died.
To Become an Astronaut
(Hi last words were for you to have this book.
Seems like he was so sick that he could barely run.
Hey don't you think Kamogawa san's kind of cold?
Even though she's got a weird personality
shouldn't she at least show some tears?
I heard she said some harsh things to SNmazo-kon before.
Who does she think she is?
That tree's flowers don't bloom.
When those cherry blossoms bloom. I'll show you my drawing.
What he saw from that window every
day was you running, little one.
Since a long time ago.
Lion-san...
Peep in my heart...
It really hurts...
Yuigahama Clinic
I promise I'll go there someday.
Let's meet in space, Shimazu-kun.
Preview
I saw Marikachah smiling brightly for the first time.
Pvt if was only in a photograph.
AO I said was that it was cute
but I ended up getting her angry at me.
I wonder why-
And to think, we have to start our next
round of training feeling like this...
Next time oh Twin Sptea: Survival Training.
Next time oh Twin Spica: Survival Training.
Surviv 1 I raining
Survival Trailing