On a spring night Virgo is spread o«twM4y.
My favorite star Spica, is this Alpha star.
If you stretch this line from the Mg
Pipper, there's the North Star.
And if you pod the handle of the ladle...
there's the star of the cow herder, Arcturus, then Spica!
This line is ealled the Oreat Are of Spring.
Iry looking for ft in the southern sky!
Puring the cherry blossom season
try looking for it in the southern sky!
Vuring the cherry blossom season
Survival Training
Its not here. .
That's weird... Where did it go?
What are you looking for, little one?
Well you see... I promised to lend Kei-chan a book...
but I seem to have bet it somewhere around here...
Oh... that sounds pretty troublesome.
Ah, thaft it
I was wondering where it was...
but you had ft all -this time, Uo*isa*t!
Th Thafs wot it
That girl -from last week was reading this book.
Kei-chan?
Not hr... the other person.
You mean Marikachan?
Yeah... her.
I	ML
Marika-thaii was reading this baekthen~
How is she doing?
Huh?
Is she doing all right*
W-What is H*
So lioH Sa* only looks skfo-deep!
Well I guess since Marika-chaw is so pretty...
I K S nothing like that!
I was Just... a bit eoiicenied, that's ail...
Yes, yes...
Let's Just leave ft as that.
No, you've got ft wrong!
Asvmi chan!
What are you doing? You'd be late!
Hvh? Its this late already?
I'm rowing now!
Okay.
I'm confiscating this!
It is wy book after all right?
Huh?
it's Marika-chan!
I wonder it she used it as a bookmark.
Marikachan laugh like this.
Now that I think of it, I've never seen
Come on, Asumi-chan!
Yes!
Well I'm going!
I'm sorry Ringo-san!
You're jo slow!
It eoiridHt be... right?
Wh't do you meant
I don't want to.
I definitely don't want to!
Promise you'll quit it something happens.
Fainting at school is out of the question!
I told you I don't want to!
I won't ever quit.
Fm saying this became I'm worried about you.
Not taking your medicine, and on top of all this, fainting...
There is no way I could let you out in the open.
Yoo're worried about'm t
Of course.
Isn't it because you'll be the one in trouble
it something happens to me?
If yoo have no intention of listening to me...
then I have my own ideas on what to do about this!
If you try to pull strings behind my bade.
I'd leave this house.
You'd belter think of what would happen if I were to do that.
Is that the way you should be speaking to your father7!
The real Marika would never have taken an attitude like that.
Stop saying it like that.
Why are you always Hce that doing these...
top it!
You're the owe who keeps saying the same things!
I'm myself!
Why... don't you understand?!
Marika!
She's here.
Safe!
Good morning.
How unusual for you to be rushing
in right at the last minute, Asumi.
Ah, I was looking for something, so...
Here, Kei-chan!
The book I promised to show you.
AM thank you!
I really wanted to read this.
Someone for whom it's even more unusual Just eame.
She's usually the first one here, too.
Ladies probably oversleep sometimes, don't you think?
(rood iHoroitfq, Marika-cban.
Good morning.
This...
It was tn a book in the storage room tlhedorm.
It was in a book in the storage room at the dorm.
J
You must have forgotten it when you came over last time.
It's a nlee photo!
let's see. let's see.
It's taken very wdL
Don't you think Marika-chan's smfle is cute?
Pont Just look at ft as you please!
V Umni... fw sorry, Marika-chan
Pot I reafly thought ft was a nice photo...
What would you know?
Quit meddling in my business.
Hey!
We were the ones that saw it without asking.
Asumi hasn't done anything!
Marika-chan...
Everyone, listen up!
Everyone get changed into your gym
clothes and meet in the study room.
Huh? Was first period Physical Education?
No, maybe there was a change in schedule...
What7! We're going to have to run again?
You're against running that much?
N Not at alL how absurd of yoo to say.
Sadly it isn't a marathon.
You eaii be at ease.
What is tWs?
Pe quiet!
This is Nakazawasan who belongs to
the JAMSF PewJopment Pepartwent.
Nat to mart you.
Well then, please go ahead...
This is a one-man capsule for an emergency escape.
In ease there is a problem with the spaee station or shuttle...
in spaee for a short period of time.
this has been created to provide a refuge
Within the capsule, there are approximately
It hours worth of oxygen...
~and though meager, some food and water.
Also, there is an assortment of tools.
To take them oof, press this area
like tWi and the cover will open
Are there any questions?
vmm...
Ya, go on.
There's a little something that I've been wondering about...
How do we get back to the space shuttle
after we escape with that?
You cannot go back.
You wH have to wait until help arrives.
Noway!
That sucks...
Seriously?
If yoo are placed bi a situation where you most use this...
you wffl need a certain amount of resignation.
Because there's also the chance that
you eould be left behind in space.
No... I don't even want to think about thai!
And so, you will all go into the capsule to try it out.
are slightly claustrophobic, but...
It way be tough for those of you who
this is another part of your training.
Pamn ft, a test of endurance, huh?
The maximum length it't honri
It'll end sometime before the oxygen runs out, don't you think?
Hmpf you sure are ealm about this.
Understand, everyone?
ft sure you don't come out until the blue
lamp inside the capsule turns on.
Okay, okay... I understand...
ljost have to do it, right*
Ah, waft, wait!
Everyone, before you go hi, put this oh.
Until the training ends...
.absolutely do not drop this...
or lose this.
Panrn ft...
Understand?
What is lW*;
If we lose it, will it really be that much of a problem?
Lose if?
Inside this small capsule
ThU might be...
It looks like ft's not going to be claustrophobic
at all for you, huh, Kamogawa*
Hub?
Now everyone dose your batch!
Don't forget to engage the lock!
See you later, Asumi...
Yeah.
Marika-chan...
It's pitch black...
I don't know what's where wrth this darkness...
OK it's on.
They said something about the blue lamp turning on -
They said something about the blue lamp turning on...
Status Display Light
they said something about the blue lamp turning on...
but I wonder how long I have to wait...
What is this? Geez!
We're being moved elsewhere?
Ow!
H seems to have been shaking for a while-
Jxrt is that the kind of training its supposed to be?
Ow...
The shaking stopped.
I fed nauseous...
I wonder bow long it's been...
The blue lamp still hasn't turned on, either...
I'm falling?!
0W, ow, ow, ow, ow...
Status Display Light
The blue lamp!
It's over at last!
It's so blight...
Huh?
Why am I in a place like this?
Kei-chan!
Marika-chan!
Everyone!
No one's here...
Int.. al alone.
Could this be~?
Survival Training Contents."
Supposing that during lift-off, or when returning from
space, the rocket has made an emergency landing...
.assemble within five days at location
A shown on the attached map."
This is the real framing?
ltd
I guess they wouldn't make just staying
in the capsule the end of ft.
If that's the ease; why didn't they tell us in the first place?!
(reez!
Ow...
coming out from this device, aren't they?
They're checking our position using the signals
You can't call this just training.
a criterion for selecting astronauts...
From here on in, everything will probably become
Promise you O quit it something happens.
Fainting at school is out of the question!
else! I have to reaeh the goal...
I must reach the goal before anyone
There's no name pbrfe is there?
Whafs the use in cheeking?
What aw 1 trying to cheek anyway?
Whaf* left in the capsule is...
a backpack sleeping bag, vinyl sheet...
~as wefl as...
-a knife, penligbt, rope, toothpaste...
So there's no compass...
It looks as though the food and water won't even last five days...
There are really only the minimum amount
of necessary things in here.
i have to hurry and pinpoint where I ant
or I won't be able to wove forward.
be best not to wove around so much.
Itrf with this food situation, it would
I D wove in the worwing tomorrow...
And for now, I'd better set op a tent before-the sun goes down.
If I could see the stars more dearly Fd
be able to figure out my bearings...
I wonder if I've just gotten used to life in Tokyo...
It's so quiet that I can't sleep.
I wonder how everyone is doing...
When I'm like this, it reminds me of the day
I chased Lion-san deep into the forest...
That lime, it was quiet and completely dark Just like this...
I don't know why, but I couldn't stop my tears...
I fdt so lonely...
Seared, sad and al alone...
but I wanted to see him.
I just really wanted to see hint...
While I was mulling things over, ft's already become morning.
I spent Jut one summer with her.
And I vaguely remembered her face too...
Even her name...
Now that I think about ft, what was her name anyway?
Wdn't I ask her?
Well even if their faces are alike, their
ages are just too different, right?
It's probably Just we thinking too nuieh.
time to't.
AH done!
I have to brush my teeth after eating!
I'm fine.
I eaH do my best until I meet up wrth everyone again.
Was that my imagination?
I thought I heard someone's voice.
Marika...
Marika?
Preview
One person is my classmate, Marika-chan
lion-tan met when he was a ehfld.
The other is the Marika-chan that
With the times so far apart, what's their relationship?
Without knowing what that is, we wander through the forest.
Pvt during that time, Marika-chan meets someone unexpected.
Next time on Twin Spica. Marika and Marika.
Next time on Twin Spica: Marika and Marika.
Marika and Marika