On a spring night Virgo is spread out widely.
My favorite star, Spica, is this Alpha star.
If you stretch this line from the Big
Dipper, there's the North Star.
And if you pud the handle of the ladle
there's the star of the cow herder, Arcturus, then Spiea!
This line is called the Great Arc of Spring.
During the cherry blossom season
try looking for it in the southern sky!
Marika and Marika
Just as I thought, wrthout a compass, it's hard to figure out where I am or which direction I'm going in.
This... I feel like I've seen a similar rock before...
Could it be that I've been going around in circles?
Hey!
Is anyone here?
No one's here...
I wonder how everyone is doing...
Hm?
That's right!
Okay, this will work!
going down the same path I took before.
With this. I'll know without a doubt if I m
Everything's fine.
I'll get through this somehow.
Oh man! Someone do something about this!
I keep going and going, but it's just more forest.
I can't take this anymore!
Ow...
Damn it flow is this supposed to be training?
I'll definitely make them reimburse me for my glasses!
the little seagull's doing right now?
Now that that's done.. I wonder how
Is it all over for me?
I wanted to go to space...
I wanted to go to space..
I wanted to go to space~.
You can't go to space alone!
I thought I could go by myself.
I thought the only way to go was alone.
I mean, I was... always alone...
Let's promise!
it's a promise.
Pro...mise...
Yep, Marika-chan, it's a promise to graduate school together.
And a promise to go to space together!
Together?
I can... go together with people?
I can... go as well?
Of course!
Were friends with the same dream.
Surely we can definitely go together.
It's a promise.
Yes!
I just can't...
Doyour best, Marika-chan!
It's a promise!
Do your best, for your dream!
I'm always here.
I'm always with you.
So don't give up, Marika-chan!
What would you know?
Quit meddling in my business.
I... I... have to apologize..
Apologize... then... then...
I have to tell her...
that I want to go to space together, too.
That... looked like it was written a long time ago.
Nothing has changed.
It's just as it was back then.
It's just that time has passed...
Hm?
After some time, that girl stopped coming...
Her chronic disease took a turn for the worse...
.and she was to leave the country to get some treatment.
I wanted to meet her again before that happened.
That's what I thought...
In the end that was it.
That girl never came back to this mansion.
that she died overseas or something.
After a while, the adults were gossiping
I knew of those rumors... but who knew
If that was even true or not.
They're so alike, it looks as it she was reborn anew.
And the little one's friend also had
the same name as her... Marika.
Is it just by chance?
Or...
It must be a coincidental resemblance.
First of all, even with the same name, this Marika
and that Marika's ages are too different.
It's not like she's a ghost, like me.
Oops.
Did I break it?
Ukita... Marika...
Then... she's...
It can't be... such a thing...
I won't give in...
Not at a place like this...
I don't want to give up.
I walked around all day...
but it definitely seems much larger than the map showed.
I'd be able to clearly tell where I am...
If I could at least find this river
I don tthink the direction that the sun rose was wrong, but...
and move forward tomorrow.
I'll just have to leave this tent behind
Even if I have to go a long way I need to go
to a high place and confirm my location.
Hey you're really there, right?
Hey Lion-san!
Lion-san!
The sea!
Thank goodness. Now I can begin to find out where I am.
The first emergency landing site is around here...
The sea is on this side.
A small hill in front...
That means I'm on this mountain-..
If that's the case, it seems like there
isn't much distance to the goal but...
The time I have to make it there is limited...
.and with these mountain paths, it might take me all five days.
Speaking of which, I wonder if there's some
sign or flag to mark where location A is...
It doesn't say anything here..
I wonder how everyone is doing.
Now that I think about it, since I came to the Space
School I never really had a meal by myscIf.
I'm by myself right now.
This is the real me.
You ran too fast in the beginning.
That's why you became exhausted halfway.
Put I wanted to reach the goal quickly!
That sort of feeling is also important...
but I always make sure to reach
the goa|with half of my strength.
Half of my strength?
To go to space, you need a lot of friends, right?
That swhy I leave halfof my strength for the rest of the crew.
So even if you reach the goal first...
you can go back to lend them a hand.
If you turn around to see your friend on the floor
You can't go to space alone.
Half of my strength for my friends...
For my friends who are somewhere...
The sound of water?
It's cold!
The river is flowing in this direction, so...
Thank goodness. It's just as I thought.
If I go this way...
Someone was here.
Hey! Anyone!
Is anybody there?
That person must be like me...
Moving toward the goal marked as location A on the map.
1 wasn't alone after all. I wasn't alone!
Everyone's doing their best here.
I have to go as well!
Ow!
My feet won't hold out...
It must be because I haven't eaten anything since yesterday.
Huh?
Would I be able to eat it?
But if I get sick from it...
I won't do it!
Not here anymore
Is anyone nearby?
Isn't anyone here?
As I thought, they wouldn't be here.
That person would have gone ahead already.
I wonder who was here.
I wonder if that person has already reached location A...
I'll have to do my best or I'll be left behind by everyone.
Blood?
Hashimoto General Hospital
W-Where is this?
Me...?
Marika.
I told you. Don't leave this room without permission.
But, Father...
I will not tolerate back-talk.
If it was the real Marika, this wouldn't have happened.
Why?
Why does he cay that?
I'm myself.
i'm Marika.
You're mistaken.
I didn't want that Marika
She's completelywrong.
If I was going to have such painful feelings..
I didn't need that Marika.
An unwanted child.
It so, why give birth to me?
If I'm not allowed to be myself...
Where should I go?
Someone... someone save me!
Take me away from here.
Please!
Kamog wa-san...
Are you all right?
Who are youT
I was walking by the corridor...
.and I heard you call my friend's name in your delirium.
Me?
Yes.
The name ofmy old dear friend... so I couldn't help it.
Sorry.
Urn, what did I cay?
AsumL"
Asumi?
Preview
Kasane-chan treasured the leaf star from that day.
Kacane-chan treasured the leaf star from that day.
Her feelings must have connected with me.
What Marika-chan told Kasaneehan
was an unexpected secret.
And even if I reach the goal...
There's still something I have to do, right?
Next time on Twin Spica: What I Can Do For You Now.
What I Can Do For You Now