On a spring night, Virgo is spread out widely.
My favorite star, Spica, is this Alpha star.
If you stretch this line from the Big
Dipper, there's the North Star.
And if you pull the handle of the ladle...
there's the star of the cow herder, Arcturus, then Spica!
This line is called the Great Arc of Spring.
During the cherry blossom season
try looking for it in the southern sky!
What I Can Do For You Now
Who are you?
And this place...
I'm Shibata Kasane.
My mother's currently hospitalized here, so...
Hospital?
I see... I collapsed, and then this...
Hey, I overheard a little of what was going on...
You're a student of the Space School?
Y-Yes.
Could it be that you're from the newly
established Astronaut Training Course?
That's right, but...
I knew it!
Then, Asumi-chan's there too, right?
I see... she's having her child hood dreams come true.
You're really Kamogawa-san's friend?
Huh?
I mean... you didn't even know which school she attended...
That's true...
It's strange, isn't it?
Asumi-chan was my friend from
when I was still living in Yuigahama.
I ended up moving, and that was the end of it, so...
I'm not sure it she still remembers me.
But, to me, she's a very dear person that I can't forget.
Night on the Galactic Railroad
Miyazawa Kenji
Even though the distance between us has widened...
every time I see this leaf star. I've always remembered...
that Asumi-chan has always been with me.
Huh? It ended...
The blood trails off here...
It someone's here, answer me!
Are you all right?
With this amount of blood. If the person was hurt...
Hey!
I have to look for them...
But where else am I supposed to look?
I don't even have a compass, so if I go around
searching now, I might be the one that gets lost.
What should I do?
What am I supposed to do?
Lion-san...
A leaf star?
There aren't any maple trees here,
so where did it come from?
Little one, you'll have to do all that you can do now.
Just like you've always done.
That time, I really wanted to do more for Kasane-chan...
but at the time, that was the best I could do.
What I can do now...
I'll go straight to the goal,
without taking any breaks to rest...
...and then call for help there if it's needed.
It someone's here listen to me!
I'm going to hurry to the goal
but I'll come back as soon as I can!
So please wait until then!
There's the possibility it really isn't anything too serious.
In any case, I have to get to the goal as soon as possible.
But...
It she's such a dear friend to you why didn't you
try to stay in contact with her after that?
We didn't part under the best of circumstances.
You see... because of the Lion accident, my father died.
Because I was also hospitalized for
burns, I couldn't make any friends.
Asumi-chan was the only one
who became friends with me.
But I said a lot of horrible things...
Asumi-chan didn't do anything wrong at all.
yet I said do many horrible things to her...
apologize we suddenly decided to move...
And then before I had a chance to
...and that was how it ended.
Why?
How can you still day she's dear to you?
How can you still day that you were always together?
It could just be that only you think of her that way.
She might still be angry and might not forgive you.
Yeah... that's true. It could just be my own selfishness.
But I don't know why... even now, I still believe in her.
was the one that gave me what I really wanted the most.
Because, though I couldn't say it at the time Asumi-chan
What you really wanted?
Yes.
A real friend.
A real friend...
Judging by how far I've gone
I should be close to the goal but...
There's only a little water left.
I'll just have to endure without it in ease of an emergency.
I can still endure a little further...
Just a little bit more until the goal... just a little bit more...
Hashimoto General Hospital
Ukita-san, I see you've woken up.
Ukita Marika
How do you feel?
Is there any place that hurts?
No, I'm all right.
Well, I'll go call the doctor over then.
And I'll take my leave here too.
Wait!
Don't go yet.
I... I also have to apologize to Kamogawa-san...
but I don't know it she'll forgive me.
But I don't know what to do...
She told me that I couldn't go to space alone...
She told me "Let's go to space together," so...
We promised it, so...
So...
I want to apologize... I have to apologize.
But it wouldn't be possible for us to become friends.
Because... because no one needs me!
I was never wanted by anyone!
I... I... I'm an unwanted child!
There's no one who's not needed.
Why do you think that?
Did someone tell you that?
I see... it must have been painful...
Why am I crying?
That's something I already know...
But you know, the words that come out of
someone's mouth aren't necessarily the truth.
Not everyone can express their feelings well in words.
What's most important is...
your heart.
I had someone who was my sister as well as my mother...
who had the same name as me...
I never told this to anyone before...
because I was told not to...
but that person died, and I'm still here.
I'm actually here, but no one will look at me.
Even if you aren't needed where you
are right now, that's not your fault.
It isn't anyone's fault.
It's just that surely there is
someone that needs you somewhere.
When the time comes, you just have to do the
best you can to be of help to that person.
Like Asumi-chan.
I've lived this entire time
thinking that, wanting to be like her.
The next time I get to meet Asumi-chan...
I want to be someone who smiles
who can tell her that I'm doing my best.
But when that happens, it doesn't matter
If Asumi-chan thinks I'm her friend or not.
Of course I'll be happy if I see her
but it's all right if we can't meet.
She has always been inside my heart, looking after me.
You're with Asumi-chan now, right?
Treasure this time you have.
Wouldn't that be enough for you and Asumi-chan?
Ukita!
Are you all right?
I'll go now.
Can I see you again?
Yes.
Judging from where I am right now...
South is this way...
So the goal is on that side.
I'm still all right.
It's just a little further...
The goal area!
Thank goodness! I made it in time.
Asumi?
Asumi! Asumi!
Asumi!
Kei-chan!
I'm so glad you're alive!
Fuchuuya-kun and Suzuki-kun too.
So you're finally here.
Did you guys just make it here?
What are you saying, being so easygoing about this?
All three of us made it here yesterday.
Huh?
The others are on the other side of that flag...
with tents set up waiting
for anyone who might be injured.
So then, everyone reached the goal. Thank goodness.
Even the person who got hurt got this far.
Really... because of Kei's worrying, we had
to go back and forth from hereto there seven times!
No, it was eight times.
Hearing that makes me more tired!
Be quiet. You're the one that tagged along, Fucchi!
She got you there.
Shut up!
Ah! Your glasses.
Don't take so long to notice!
S-sorry.
Huh?
A compass...
Is something wrong with this compass?
Hm? It's nothing...
I was just a little surprised.
Surprised by what?
Was it just missing in my capsule?
I'm hungry.
I'm tired as well.
But it's a good thing that it's been sunny.
If the weather had turned bad, it would have
been difficult in the forest without a compass.
Surprised?
It couldn't be that the little seagull
came all the way here without a compass...
I will bring Ukita Marika back with me.
What's the current situation?
Hashimoto General Hospital
All the students have arrived at location A.
All right. Well then, start retrieving
the capsules and the students now.
Yes.
The Ukita Marika I met long ago...
...is the little one's friend, Ukita Marika.
If the two are the same person
I can only think of one possibility.
It she knows the secret of her birth...
Ukita Marika, you are a very strong girl.
You're with Asumi-chan now, right?
Treasure this time you have.
Wouldn't that be enough for you and Asumi-chan?
But I dropped out from the training.
It may be that I can't go to space together with her.
That's it for me.
I'm starving to death.
I want some barbecue...
Kalbl, salted tongue, liver slices...
Don't talk about food, you moron!
Kei-chan, eat this.
Huh? Why do you have so much, Asumi?
You have quite a bit there!
Were you feeling sick?
No, I had resolved to keep half
of it until I reached the goal.
Huh?
I lost.
I'm completely defeated by the little seagull.
What are you laughing about?
Geez! I don't get either of you!
But, you really don't mind if we eat this?
Yeah.
Japanese sweets from home for free.
Asumi! I'll give you all my
Kei-chan, was there anyone that was injured?
Like someone who had a bloody wound...
Blood?
No one's eaten anything since
yesterday so they're dead tired...
But there wasn't anyone who was injured.
Has something happened?
Yes, on the way here, there was someone's capsule.
And there were bloodstains there.
But it's good that everyone reached the goal safely.
I'm relieved.
There's still one person who isn't here.
Huh?
Ukita-san still hasn't come.
Marika-chan?
But it doesn't necessarily mean that that was Marika...
Don't think of anything strange, Kamogawa.
Asumi!
There's no use going, little seagull.
She probably won't be there anymore.
But...
Look.
You've noticed it too, right?
This is a transmitter with personal data inside.
Huh? S-so that's what it was.
With these, all of the instructors
should know where we are at all times.
It's a good thing I didn't lose it.
You'd better get used to it soon, the way this school does things.
So if Ukita-san had an immobilizing injury...
the rescue party would have already gotten to her.
But...
Moreover, this is the last day of the survival training.
If you move away from the goal area now...
you won't be able to return here by the end of today.
No matter what reason, it would
probably be a great demerit.
Demerit?
It's as Shuu says, Asumi!
Let's wait here.
Kamogawa, it could be that your
dream of going to space would be ruined,
Yeah...
All right, we're going back.
Yeah, I'm sure our ride back will come soon.
We can finally go home!
When I get back, it'll be barbecue for me!
What I can do now...
Oh yeah!
Hey Asumi when we get back, on our next day off...
Asumi?
Huh?
That dummy!
Tokyo National Space School
Sensei, there's something...
What's wrong?
Well... a student is moving away.
What?
There is a student moving further away from location A.
There's no sign of her stopping.
What is the name of the student?
It's coming up right now.
Kamogawa Asumi
It is Kamogawa Asumi.
What?
Where is she trying to go, after having reached the goal?
Hell if I know.
Anyway bring her back.
Yes.
Marika-chan!
Just how far did that dummy go?!
Just how tar did that dummy go?!
I forgot how fast she was...
That's not all.
There's no hesitation in her run.
The little seagull clearly remembers
where she has gone before.
Asumi! Where are you?!
Are you guys all right?
This isn't all right!
Damn it, what's that dummy thinking?
About her friend, of course.
Ow...
You know...
Besides, we're also the ones thinking about her.
Asumi!
Really...
to space may be tested right now.
Little one your dream of going
Marika-chan, please be all right!
Now you have friends with the
same dream as you, little one.
So it's all right.
I'm sure you'll be able to do it.
Preview
Mom, I'll introduce you to everyone.
Marika-chan, and Lion-san.
This is Fuchuuya-kun, Kei-chan, Suzuki-kun
They're all my dear friends.
So, I'm all right.
Don't worry, Mom.
Twin Spica, final episode. Gaze into Tomorrow.
Gaze into Tomorrow