Mom.
It's me, Asumi.
I eamefrMVW waster
I drove the rocket by myself.
There's just one thing I've always wanted to say to you.
11 say it, okay?
Mom, thank you for giving birfh to me.
Gaze Into Tomorrow
Tokyo National Space School
NtehWasemei.
Him? What's wrong?
There are three others aside from Kamogawa
who are moving away from location A.
What did you say9!
Who are they?
They are Suzuki Shuu, Fuchuuya Shinnosuke, and Oumi Kei.
I litougltt it'd be them...
(reez! Everyone in that little group going together.
Could it be..
Could it be that they're looking for me?
Anyway go and pick up the rest of the students at location A.
I'll see that ffs done.
There's someone looking for me*.
For something as small as that...
to wake we lWt happy...
And also...
There's still something?
Kamogawa Asumi* signal hasn't moved for a while.
Whar.
H would be all right it she's jest staying bi one plaee~
but it could be that she dropped her transmitter.
Hey!
w
Just in case, one of you go to the scene.
Yes!
Hm*
Oo	oh, Ukfta.
IH wring all five of your weeks after this, though.
Which way should we go?
Who knows... ask her feet.
If it were you, Fuccht where would you go?
What do you mean by where
1	have a feeling that the little seagull will
definitely go baek to UkHa dan's capsule.
And then from there* try to find signs of her movement again.
That's true!
Thai, let's do that as well!
The problem is we don't know where the capsule is.
That's true, too...
Say that first next time, will you?
She's always been like this in the past.
Whenever I get involved with her, there are always hardships.
Thai, why don't you go back to location A alone?
Tbafs difficult to do how, too, so I'll continue together with you.
It seems Wee you weren't honest with yourself in the past, either.
What do you mean by that?!
It weans just what I said.
If* like a mummy hunter turning into a mummy!
WdL walking around aimlessly is definitely a waste of time.
Attd there * also the problem of how
much of this our bodies can endure.
Then what are we going to do7!
Asumil
Marika!
Asumi!
I have no strength left...
let's eat.
Huh?
Let's start eating the rations we got from Kamogawa.
You ean il
Whaf
It'd just be a Kttte.
No!
I'm keeping this for Asumi!
Hub?
You don't have to keep all of it.
l'm keeping al of Hi
Fm keeping them all for Asumi and Marika!
Whatever, I don't get you at all.
Whaf's do funny9
It means that even all of us together are no match for the little seagull.
Now then, let's get going, Foeehi.
What's most important is your heart.
What is ttiis
It's a landmark that the little seagull put here.
Kamogawa did?
There's ho mistake.
How would you know?
The little seagull doesn't have a compass.
That's why she placed signs as she moved forward.
What do you mean?
Anyway, let's follow this sign.
Kamogawa-san wifi surely come here.
tvt with her speed, she should have already arrived here..
Where could you possibly be?
There it is.
Here, too
Kamogawa-san..
Kamogawa-san!
Marika-chan..
Uttle one.
A capsule!
Whose is ft?
This is it.
The capsule that ihe RtHe seagull was talking about.
Mood...
Yeah...
I wonder what happened to Marika...
in any case, left look for the next arrow.
UoMsan...
Are you all right, little one?
I'm fine-. just a little tired.
ltd
Hey Uoti sa*
Hm?
Was I mistaken?
About what?
I mean, I dropped out of tt»e survival training to come out here...
Marika-chan's probably been rescued like Suzuki-kun said.
What fnt doing is meaningless, right9
Is -that what you really think?
Listen to your heart.
The actions that you decided to take were never meaningless.
But...
Listen...
The many things you have done up until now...
The many people you b've met op until now...
They are al stars that shape your universe.
tars?
Kei-chan, MarHca-chan, Fuchuuya-kun, and Suzuki-kun.
To you they are all stars.
There aren't any meaningless stars, right?
That's right...
And now...
your friends can surely hear it, too.
What is this?
This is probably where the little seagull cheeked her bearings.
Bearings?
Then, she most likely went straight to the goal from here.
This means that following any more arrows would be useless.
They would lead to location A.
Then, where do we look?
Asumi...
Asumi where did you go?
Geez..
I can hear something...
It's no use. I can't find her like this.
Where are you, Kamogawa-san?
What?
What was that Just how?
Uoh San...?
lion san...
It's true, I can hear it...
The sound of a harmonica...
Harmonica?
If I remember right...
I hear it... the sound of a harmonica...
Are you a dummy?
in the middle of the mountains?
Why would you hear a harmonica
I hear it Lioti-san's harmonica!
HHeyi
Lion-san?
my dad and Lion-san wffl get special free rides!
Hey let's go to where Kamogawa is.
Huh?
F Fucchi!
It's dose...
Kamogawa-san?
Asumi!
Marikacban...
I fefl asleep.
You're all right?
Yeah.
Thank goodness.
Thank goodness that you're all right, too.
You called me Asumi for the first time just now, didn't you?
I knew it You look so much cuter when yoo smile,
Hm?
I said some horrible things to yoo...
Huh?
I'm sorry...
Don't worry about it.
But...
Hey you don't hate being with everyone, right?
You're just not used to it and feel a little uncomfortable, right?
I still want to talk wrth you wore about lots and lots of things.
Talc about the stars, about space*.
And 1 stfl haven't heard your dream.
Asumi!
Marika!
Kei-chan!
Fuchuuya-kun and Suzuki-kun, tool
Asumil
thank goodness!
Italy... don't make os worry so moeh abort you.
I believed that you two would be fine, though.
Thank you, everyone.
Oumi Kei
Oumi Kei.
spend their lives knowing nothing but the Earth.
It's a little frustrating that most people have to
When I saw the picture taken from Apoto at the moon...
I got such a mysterious feeling inside of me.
You can still take pictures, even on the Moon.
It's a place that actually exists.
I want to go to the Moon, too.
I want to take a picture oh tin Moon.
I think from those dreams, I have decided
to take the path of an astronaut.
Suzuki Shuu
Suzuki Shoo.
The reason I want to go to space is that space is there.
Because stars are there.
That doesn't count as a reason?
That's stfl fbie with me.
I don't want the things that are given to me from the start.
What I want are the things I don't have yet.
Fm just that type of person, so if can't be helped.
I want to Me the stars eloser than anyone else.
Fuchuuya Shinnosuke
Fuchuuya Shinnosuke.
There are always some people who
are completely unpredictable*.
-and people who are always anxious because of those people.
thou, then they're just too unstable.
If they don't stick by watching over
If that person were to say that they'll become an astronaut...
choice but to follow the whole way.
then the other person would Have no
There way be people who go to space because of such reasons.
Ws not saying I'm one of Hiem, though...
Ukita Marika
UkHa Marika.
I thought there was ho place for me on Earth.
To me, who has never played wtth
friends or laughed with family...
the starry sky I could see from the window was more
kind and friendly than the cold human world.
When I think about my other self...
my own existence seems like ft's about to fade away.
I believed that if this was how I felt...
I'd fed more happy if I was in space by myself.
At least... until I met Asumi.
UoHm. san..
There's nothing more for me to tell you.
little one, the next age lies in all of your hands.
Lion-san..
Kamogawa Asumi
Kamogawa Asumi.
My dream is to become an astronaut...
.and go to space with Kei-chan Suzuld kun
Fuchuuya-kun, and Marika-chan
Then talk to my mother in space like this~.
Mow.
Ifs m* Asumi!
There's just oik thing Pve always wanted to say to you.
Illsa (tola ?
Mom thank you for giving Nrlti to me.
HHuh?