Faint-hearted traveler, you should pull back now
yowaki tabibito yo hikikaesu ga ii
Before you collapse
taorete shimau mae ni
But you still say that you want to go on?
sore demo omae wa iku to iu no ka
To the other side of the distant sky...
tooi sora no mukou made
Thousands of travelers have prayed to me before
ikusen no tabibito ga watashi ni inoru toki wa
After they collapsed at the end of their reckless journey
mubou ni mo tabiji ni taoreta ato na no
In a place that is not here, in a time that is not now
koko janai dokoka ni wa ima ja nai itsuka ni wa
You're searching, saying that there's love there
omae ga sagashiteru ai ga aru to iu no
Even though you could just patiently wait
watashi ga ataeta unmei no moto de
For the destiny that I have given you
otonashiku shitereba ii no ii
Do you know? I'm a Venus.
Faint-hearted traveler, come close to me
yowaki tabibito yo chikazuite oide
Come sit at my feet
watashi no hizamoto made
I will embrace you, and show you
dakishimete ageyou misete ageyou
What is waiting  beyong the distant sky
tooi sora no sono saki wo
What, you wanna go? I will make it happen.
Look up at the stars in the night
miagete goran yoru no hoshi wo
The little stars, with their little lights
chiisa na hoshi no chiisa na hikari ga
Are singing of humble happiness
sasayaka na shiawase wo utatteru
Look up at the stars in the night
miagete goran yoru no hoshi wo
Just like us, the stars without names
bokura no you ni na mo nai hoshi ga
Are praying for humble happiness
sasayaka na shiawase wo inotteru