My dream!
Year 1,Class 1, Kamogawa Asumi.
My dream is to become a rocket driver!
That's because I've heard that the Earth is very pretty when you look at it from space.
So I want to become a rocket driver and go into space!
I want to take people to all sorts of different planets!
And when they're on my rocket...
...my dad and Lion-san will get special free rides!
The end!
One Step Toward the Stars
That finishes off the examinations.
Tokyo National Space School
Entrance Exam Meeting Place
Now, I'd like all of you in the Astronaut Training Course...
...to please wait here in the classroom a little longer.
Thank you for waiting so long.
We will now be transferring you all to another place.
Take your belongings and proceed to the front of the school.
Eh? We're going somewhere else now?
That wasn't the last exam earlier?
Buses?
Where are we going?
Now then, first find out and confirm which bus you will be riding on.
What the heck is all this?
I wonder where they're planning on taking us...
Watch the chatter.
Your names are posted over there.
I can't see!
Excuse me.
Excuse me for a moment.
There it is!
Kamogawa Asumi
Bus 1, huh?
Fuchuuya Shinnosuke
Kamogawa Asumi
M-Moron!
Kamogawa, you're not on that one!
Fuchuuya-kun!
She found me, huh?
H-Hey!
What are you doing here?
What am I...
I'm taking the test too.
What?! You didn't say anything about that!
Boy, that really surprised me!
For you to be taking the Space Academy test too...
I thought for sure that you would be continuing your family business.
Like I could work in the fireworks business.
Why? I think it would suit you...
Don't say that, moron.
Eh?
It looks like that's where we are headed.
Why is this...
I've seen this before.
Huh?
This same rocket...
Somewhere...
Well of course you have.
They've been on the news and in the papers a lot before.
It's a standard multi-stage rocket...
...and you can find those in the books you're always carrying around.
Although it's not like I'm always watching you or anything.
But that's not it...
Those of you in the back, can you hear me?
Looks like you can.
Sorry for not telling you earlier, but I'm Tanaka,
an examiner for the Tokyo Space School.
Now then, I'll explain about the secondary examination that you are all about to take.
Um, wasn't the exam earlier the last of them?
Because there were so many successful applicants from the primary examination...
...we quickly added a practical examination for you.
We have contacted your relatives for you...
...so there is no need to worry about them.
A practical exam now?
What the heck is going on?
Like this could be hurriedly prepared when there's so much detail put into it?
They're just trying to keep us all off-balance.
All of you applicants will now enter the simulated residence module...
...and undergo a closed-environment adaptation test.
You will be allotted a gym suit in exchange for your examination application ticket...
...so change in your individual changing rooms and head for your assigned rooms...
...not forgetting your room number.
The test will be explained to you in detail when you all arrive in your rooms.
That is all.
Does anyone have any questions about anything so far?
If not...
E-Excuse me!
May I ask a question?
Go ahead.
Can that rocket fly?
Really, this girl...
Quiet!
Right now, this has become the Space Academy...
...but this was originally the home of the Space Museum...
...so what you see there was made for all of the children who visited to enjoy...
...and it is nothing more than a full-scale model rocket.
Model...
So there is no chance of it ever flying.
Are there any more questions?
So this is where the next test will take place, huh?
Hey, look at that kid!
Huh? Which one?
Does he think this is a sightseeing tour or something?
Hmph, that guy will just fail straight out anyway!
Is there something stuck on my face?
N-No, I'm sorry.
There's nothing on it.
She's surprised because you don't have any eyebrows!
Pretty unusual though, female applicants...
Is there something wrong with that?
Ah, I know. You can have this.
A walnut?
You can have one too.
If you want to do any extravehicular activity...
...you'd better strengthen your grip.
Since you're a girl, I won't say you have to use one hand, but...
At least enough that you can crack them with both hands, you know?
See ya! I hope you can become a seagull as well.
What was with him?
Spouting nonsense like that...
What does he mean, seagull?
"Ya chaika!"
Huh?
It's Russian.
It means "I'm a seagull."
It was the call sign of the first woman to fly into space, Valentina Tereshkova!
Y-You... That's amazing!
We should get going too!
Astronaut Training Course
Examinee Number
Name
Katou
Shun'ichi
M
F
Next person.
Number 1710. Make sure not to forget it.
Take this with you. Your room number is 2150.
Okay, next!
Your room number is 0350. Make sure not to forget it.
Okay.
What's your size?
Um, SS.
Oh, shoot.
Huh?
There are no SS clothes.
We only brought down to S size.
Well then, S is fine.
Next person.
Yes!
Oh, sorry, sorry!
Do your best.
Room number 2960. Make sure not to forget it.
Right!
Female Changing Room
Hey, what do you think they're going to make us do here?
Some sort of closed-environment test, they said...
I'm really anxious...
Oh, geez! There's no cell phone reception in here at all!
Really?! Geez, how depressing...
It's still a little too big...
0350... 0350...
Just as I thought!
This is great, Lion-san!
This exam might just be lucky for me!
Hey!
Don't just stand there, come on in!
We can't even introduce ourselves if you just stand in the doorway.
Yeah.
My name's Oumi Kei.
Nice to meet you!
I'm Kamogawa Asumi.
Wow, it's so small!
We're in the same year, right?
Ah, I'm 14 now.
I was born early in the year.
How about you, Oumi-san?
I was born early as well...
Ah, sorry for staring like that!
Also, you can just call me Kei.
Huh?
My name. Don't call me Oumi, call me Kei!
Okay, Kei... chan.
Well then, you can call me Asumi as well.
Okay!
Ah, I haven't asked the other girl's name yet.
She seems kinda hard to approach.
It's kind of hard with that type of person, don't you think?
Excuse me...
I'm Kamogawa Asumi.
I had heard that there weren't many girls in the Astronaut Training Course...
...so I was a little anxious about this.
So I'm not really sure I should say I'm relieved, but I'm happy...
I hate that.
Trying to get all friendly like that...
Isn't there something else you should be doing first?
Something I should be doing?
The handle on that door that you just came through...
How many people do you think have touched it?
People checking the room for the test...
...applicants who got the wrong room...
There have to have been quite a few of them.
You clasped that door handle for more than ten seconds.
In other words, your right hand is covered in the dirty handprints and bacteria of ten people.
The first thing that you should do in this closed environment is keep it clean.
At the very least, you shouldn't be shaking hands with anyone.
Hey now!
I was listening to all that, but who do you think you are?!
That was saying too much no matter how you look at it!
Hey, are you listening?!
Kei-chan, it's no big deal!
Um, I'm sorry, okay?
We will now begin the closed-environment adaptation test.
It's begun!
After you have confirmed that there are three applicants in your individual rooms...
...please push the red button next to the door only once.
Red button?
This?
The door disappeared...
I'm sure it'll open again if you press the button again.
Stop that!
What are you thinking?
The test has already begun.
They didn't tell you to push it twice, did they?
Use your head before you do anything else.
Now, I will explain the details of the test.
The three members in each room will each be one team...
...and will spend the seven days of this test together in this closed environment.
Se-Seven days? In this place?
You're kidding me!
Be quiet. I can't hear!
At 9 o'clock at night, the lights will automatically turn off.
At 6 o'clock in the morning, they will automatically turn back on.
Meals and clothes for the seven days are provided for you on the shelves next to the beds.
Please confirm this.
It's true. They're all here.
You are not to spend the seven days here doing nothing.
As a group project, you are to complete something within the seven allotted days.
Something?
The project is contained in the white box that is located in the comer of each room.
This must be it.
Yeah.
That box must be opened by inputting the room number that your team has been assigned.
There is no second chance, so please be careful.
Also, if there is an unavoidable reason that you cannot complete the project...
...or if you are unable to continue either mentally or physically...
...or if there is an emergency situation...
...you can stop the test and open the door by pressing the red button mentioned earlier.
However, no matter what the circumstances, if you push this button again in these seven days...
...all three members of the team will fail the test.
What?
Those teams who have already pressed the button again...
If this were the real thing you would already have failed.
This one time only, we will simply treat this as a demerit against you.
This is the end of the explanation.
Good luck in your efforts.
Hey, wake up!
Are you even planning on doing anything, bastard?!
I am.
Liar!
You slept through the whole explanation without listening at all!
I was listening!
I just haven't gotten enough sleep.
My girlfriend just wouldn't let me sleep last night.
Huh?
So you're gonna say that your bruise there is because she hit you, saying not to go, then?
Really, bringing up nonsense like that...
I never said you could go to that school!
Well, the "saying not to go" part was certainly true.
Huh?
So, what are we doing now?
This guy really wasn't listening!
The project for the test is inside of this box...
...but it won't open until you input the room number.
We only have one chance, so no trying again.
Ah, so that's why they said not to forget our room numbers.
The person typing it in will have a grave responsibility.
What, leaving it to others again, you eyebrow-shaving jerk?
How cruel!
I have a great name, Suzuki Shuu, that you can use.
Understand my great style, okay?
What great style is that?
So, can you remember it?
Well, I remembered the owl so...
Wait, what is that?
The owl that goes "hoot, hoot"?
That's right.
You could remember Sagittarius as well, really.
Would you cut this stuff out?!
What connection is there between an owl and a constellation?!
Hey, keep it down!
Don't blame me if I push it wrong, here.
I was wondering why the room numbers were all mixed up like that...
I can't remember everything like that!
Geez...
It's all right, Kei-chan.
I remember it clearly.
Really? Nice going, Asumi!
Hold on one second there.
I don't trust you enough to leave my fate to you just yet...
Fate!?
You've been making too big a deal of this the whole time!
First off, does that mean that you remember it?
It's all right.
It will definitely be fine.
l can say that with confidence.
Asumi, you really do remember it, right?
Yeah.
There's no way I'd mess it up.
No way.
Well, then I'll leave it to you...
Although it doesn't really matter, since I don't remember.
Splendid!
That's amazing! Wow!
Really, who's the one leaving things to others?
So, what's inside?
Huh?
What is this?
How many times did you press the button right when I was telling you not to, you moron?!
Hey, you forgot the room number too, didn't you?
It's easy to forget such random numbers like that...
It's not like this is a quiz show or anything.
Oh, God!
You did it!
I knew you could do it, Asumi!
Now, let's see...
All right!
I-It's heavy!
Hey!
Don't just stand over there!
Why don't you try helping us?!
Asumi?
Ouch!
Domino pieces...?
Preview
The secondary exam of the Astronaut Training Course...
Days of doing nothing but lining up dominoes behind closed doors...
Our three lives are filled with nervousness,
carrying on with impatience.
Then, when we thought that the test would end this way...
...something we never expected to happen takes place on the fourth day!
And then I...
Next time on Twin Spica: Memory of a Distant Day.
Memory of a Distant Day