Faint-hearted traveler, you should pull back now
yowaki tabibito yo hikikaesu ga ii
Before you collapse
taorete shimau mae ni
But you still say that you want to go on?
sore demo omae wa iku to iu no ka
To the other side of the distant sky...
tooi sora no mukou made
Thousands of travelers have prayed to me before
ikusen no tabibito ga watashi ni inoru toki wa
After they collapsed at the end of their reckless journey
mubou ni mo tabiji ni taoreta ato na no
In a place that is not here, in a time that is not now
koko janai dokoka ni wa ima janai itsuka ni wa
You're searching, saying that there's love there
omae ga sagashiteru ai ga aru to iu no
Even though you could just patiently wait
watashi ga ataeta unmei no moto de
For the destiny that I have given you
otonashiku shitereba ii no ii
Do you know? I'm a Venus.
Faint-hearted traveler, come close to me
yowaki tabibito yo chikazuite oide
Come sit at my feet
watashi no hizamoto made
I will embrace you, and show you
dakishimete ageyou misete ageyou
What is waiting beyond the distant sky
tooi sora no sono saki wo
What, you wanna go? I will make it happen.
Our country's first manned exploratory space rocket, the Lion, was launched.
However, 72 seconds after liftoff…
…the liquid fuel booster suddenly exploded.
And although the Space Control Center activated what could be called its self-destruct system…
…the flight suspension system did not function correctly.
The Lion fell into an urban area and caused a huge disaster with many civilian casualties.
Five years later…
Launching Fireworks
In mourning
Hey, hey. I heard that Kamogawa's wife died.
Yes. They said that the funeral is tomorrow.
She had been in that state for quite a while, hadn't she?
That's right.
Oh my, so that means it's just father and child?
Asumi-chan just entered elementary school, too.
How sad for them.
Yuigahama Fireworks Display
Kamogawa
Asumi!
Asumi, where are you?
Excuse me, I'm Suzunari, Asumi-chan's teacher at Yuigahama Elementary.
My condolences on your recent loss.
Um, is something wrong?
Sensei, have you seen Asumi around?
Huh?
Has something happened to Asumi-chan?
Well, you see…
…she took the cremated ashes and went off somewhere.
Eh?
You can't see it from here.
Hey Mister, what's your job?
Ｙｕｉｇａｈａｍａ　Ｓｈｒｉｎｅ
An advertising mascot?
Or maybe someone from the circus?
You… You can tell who I am?
I don't know, so that's why I'm asking!
Now this is surprising.
You can see me, little one?
Is it strange for me to see you?
Well, I am a ghost, after all.
No way!
What a strange old man!
It's the truth.
Besides, don't call me old man.
Even if I look like this, I'm still young and strong!
This T-shirt shows my fashion sense, you see?
Ｙｕｉｇａｈａｍａ　Ｓｈｒｉｎｅ
You think so?
Hey, why are you wearing that thing?
There are a lot of reasons behind it.
Let me see your face!
I can't!
Little one, what is that box that you're carrying?
This? Well you see…
It's my mom.
What?
Asumi-chan!
So this is where you went.
It's Suzunari-sensei.
Your father is looking for you.
Let's go home.
Right.
Hey, will you be here tomorrow too?
Yeah.
Great! Bye-bye, then.
Is there someone there?
That's right!
I didn't ask for your name!
My name? Let's see…
You can just call me Lion.
Lion-san? What a weird name!
See you!
Wa… Asumi-chan?
Who was she talking with?
Asumi-chan, were you with someone back there?
Yeah! Umm…
He had a strange-looking lion head!
He said he was a ghost!
Lion? A ghost?
Sometimes I just can't seem to keep up with this girl.
Suzunari-sensei, huh?
Kamogawa
Truly, my condolences on your recent loss.
I'm sorry for causing so much trouble today, sensei.
Hey, Asumi!
I told you that this was something very important, didn't I?
These ashes aren't a toy to be played with!
Hey, are you listening, Asumi?!
Really…
I guess being a single father is just no good.
She doesn't listen to a thing I say…
That's not…
She may not truly feel that her mother has passed away…
…because when Asumi became old enough to be aware of things…
…my wife was already in that state.
I had to raise my daughter without her knowing her mother.
Excuse me. It's rude of me to ask…
…but what kind of person was your wife?
I'm sure you remember it as well, sensei.
The rocket explosion incident five years ago.
My wife was a victim of that incident.
Asumi was still only one year old.
My wife received grave wounds on her face and head.
In the end, she passed away without regaining consciousness even once in those five years.
Asumi once said that she'd like to be able to see her mother just once.
That was last year.
After all, she had never seen her mother's face, except in pictures.
But ever since that day…
Asumi hasn't spoken once about her mother again.
At that time…
…what Asumi was thinking, how she felt…
I didn't know.
So all that has happened…
Huh?
Your mother became a star too, didn't she, Asumi-chan?
A star?
Yes. That's what I think happens.
A star, huh?
Little one, you came to see me again today.
What about school?
It's summer vacation right now.
Ah, that's right.
You seem to have a lot of free time yourself, Lion-san.
Is school fun?
Yeah. It's not bad.
Is Suzunari-sensei nice to you?
Huh? Lion-san, do you know Suzunari-sensei?
No, it's just…
I happened to see her yesterday, remember?
Sensei is very nice.
But you know…
Sometimes she gets a lonely expression…
A very lonely expression.
Oh my!
Yuuko-san!
Good day!
The stairs here are so long they really take their toll on you.
Yes.
Takano Family
My silly son must be pretty happy.
Every year at Obon…
Note: Obon is an annual Buddhist ritual in July or August to honor the spirits of a family's ancestors.
…he has such a pretty woman come visit him.
That's…
That's right, today is the day of the Yuigahama fireworks display, isn't it?
That boy wrote in a composition in elementary school…
…that his dream was to watch fireworks from space.
Afterward I heard from someone else that…
…fireworks are too small to be seen from space.
If you think about it, it's pretty obvious.
But without even realizing that, that boy went on to be an astronaut…
He really was a silly boy…
It's already been five years since then, hasn't it?
Shall we get going, Lion-san?
You'll help me, right?
Huh? Yeah.
Already five years since then, huh?
Here.
For me?
This is a figure of the Lion's mascot.
You can have it, Yuuko.
It's just a little trinket they sell at the space center's gift shop, though.
What, just a trinket, huh?
Hey, now…
Well, I guess it'll make a good memento, though.
Don't be saying things like that…
To someone who's going up soon.
Just kidding! I'm really happy.
You really do get carried away.
Just one week left, huh?
It's pretty amazing…
The youngest astronaut ever…
Hey, Yuuko…
After I get back from this flight safely…
Yeah?
Then, I'd like for us…
For us?
Ah, no, that's okay!
It's okay.
What? Now you've got me wondering!
What is it, huh?
I'll tell you after I get back.
Say it now!
Hey, come on!
I'll make sure to tell you when I get back.
No good, it has to be now!
Bus Stop
To Yuigahama
Why in the world did I say that?
A memento…
That was a pretty bad joke, wasn't it?
Hello?
Ah, Asumi-chan's father?
What? Asumi-chan took the ashes and disappeared again!?
Hey, little one.
Hold on a minute!
Geez…
I'm tired!
Lion-san, you're supposed to be younger than you look!
What a wimp!
These remains are as heavy as a person to my body!
Talking nonsense like that.
But do you want to rest for a while?
Lion-san!
Could you play that thing from yesterday?
Ah, gladly!
Little one, did you know?
Out of all the instruments…
…the harmonica was the first one to fly into space.
Space?
Yes. In 1965, the pilot of the American capsule, Gemini VI…
…wore a 3cm wide harmonica around his neck when he went up into space.
And then he sent a present of music down to Earth from space.
Lion-san, you sure know a lot about space.
Have you ever been there?
I haven't.
But the Earth must be really pretty when you see it from space.
I'll never be able to see it since I ended up like this, though.
Lion-san, could you really be a ghost?
Just once would have been fine, but I sure wanted to see it.
Asumi-chan!
Asumi-chan! Answer me if you're there!
Just a little further!
I knew it! There's a great view of it from here!
Ah, this is Suzunari.
She doesn't seem to be out here by the shore either.
I thought she might have come to the booths down here, so I asked around.
But no one said that they had seen Asumi-chan.
Yes. I'll look around here one more time.
Yes.
I wonder if Mom will be happy now.
Yeah. I'm sure she will.
Really?
Yeah.
Thank you for helping me, Lion-san.
Little one, I have a favor to ask of you as well.
Could I ask you for it?
Yeah! That's fine!
Geez, where did you go, Asumi-chan?
He had a strange-looking lion head!
This couldn't be…
A kidnapping?
Really… where could she have wandered off to?
Maybe I should contact the police now…
Dad!
The door was locked, so I—
Do you understand why I hit you?
I'm sure I told you already.
That's not a toy, it's something very important.
And yet you still keep running off with it…
Those ashes are…
I know.
They're the ashes of my mother who gave birth to me.
If you understand that, then why…
Where did you take them?
I buried them in the place with the prettiest view of the Yuigahama Bay.
What?
She seemed so lonely!
Closed up in that dark hospital room…
Then she got put in a little box when she died…
I felt so sorry for Mom!
You said it yourself, Dad!
You said Mom always loved the Yuigahama Bay, didn't you?
So…
Well… was Mom…
…happy to see the ocean again?
These stairs are so long, geez!
Yes?
What? You found her?
You found Asumi-chan?
Thank goodness!
I'm very sorry to have worried you, sensei.
Oh, and Asumi said that she had something to tell you.
Hello, sensei?
Yes, this is sensei.
What is it, this time?
Sensei, do you know Lion-san?
Lion-san said that he had something he wanted me to tell you!
Hold on, what are you talking about?
Okay, listen!
“Don't be too mean to the Lion doll, Yuuko.”
Umm…
See ya, sensei!
Hold on! Asumi-chan?
He's the only one who knows about this doll.
Yuuko!
Takano-kun…
After I get back from this flight safely, I'd like for us…
Idiot!
That's mean, going and becoming a star by yourself…
Takano-kun, that's mean!
Lion-san!
Maybe he's not here today…
Ｙｕｉｇａｈａｍａ　Ｓｈｒｉｎｅ
Hey, you fly to space on a rocket, right?
When I grow up, I'm going to be a rocket driver!
Then I'll let you ride for free, Lion-san!
So let me hear lots more stories!
Lion-san!
Look up at the stars in the night
miagete goran yoru no hoshi wo
The little stars, with their little lights
chiisa na hoshi no chiisa na hikari ga
Are singing of humble happiness
sasayaka na shiawase wo utatteru
Look up at the stars in the night
miagete goran yoru no hoshi wo
Just like us, the stars without names
bokura no you ni na mo nai hoshi ga
Are praying for humble happiness
sasayaka na shiawase wo inotteru
Preview
Winter of the third year of middle school…
We have to be deciding our futures now…
…but I'm still not sure.
I want to attend Tokyo Space School…
…and learn to be an astronaut…
…but I'm sure that my dad will be against it…
And it takes lots of money, so I think that maybe I should give up on that dream.
Next time on Twin Spica: Asumi's Dream.
Asumi's Dream