yowaki tabibito yo hikikaesu ga ii
Before you collapse
taorete shimau mae ni
But you still say that you want to go on?
sore demo omae wa iku to iu no ka
To the other side of the distant sky...
tooi sora no mukou made
Thousands of travelers have prayed to me before
ikusen no tabibito ga watashi ni inoru toki wa
After they collapsed at the end of their reckless journey
mubou ni mo tabiji ni taoreta ato na no
In a place that is not here, in a time that is not now
koko janai dokoka ni wa ima janai itsuka ni wa
You're searching, saying that there's love there
omae ga sagashiteru ai ga aru to iu no
Even though you could just patiently wait
watashi ga ataeta unmei no moto de
For the destiny that I have given you
otonashiku shitereba ii no ii
Do you know? I'm a Venus.
Faint-hearted traveler, come close to me
yowaki tabibito yo chikazuite oide
Come sit at my feet
watashi no hizamoto made
I will embrace you, and show you
dakishimete ageyou misete ageyou
What is waiting beyond the distant sky
tooi sora no sono saki wo
What, you wanna go? I will make it happen.
My dream!
Year 1, Class 1, Kamogawa Asumi.
My dream is to become a rocket driver!
That's because I've heard that the Earth is very pretty when you look at it from space.
So I want to become a rocket driver and go into space!
I want to take people to all sorts of different planets!
And when they're on my rocket...
...my dad and Lion-san will get special free rides!
The end!
Space School Entrance Ceremony
Good morning!
work shift
early shift
normal shift
late shift
That's right...
He said he had to go early today...
Mom, I'm going now.
To Asumi: When you get there, open this - Dad
Ow...
Kamogawa
Yuigahama
It's almost time, little one.
Lion-san...
Space Solar  Generator System
Space
Sky
Receiver Antenna
Earth
Microwave
Power Line
The Ministry of Science's Solar Generator Satellite Project.
It doesn't produce carbon dioxide or any other harmful byproducts.
The ultimate clean energy.
Since the Shishigou accident, they've stopped working on it.
The government has finally moved into action.
It'll take another three years for it to become reality.
In three years' time...
...it might be you who'll be moving this satellite, little one.
Hey, little one.
Are you upset about your father not making it to the entrance ceremony?
No.
Then, what is it?
Are you suddenly scared to go?
It's not like you, little one.
I always thought that I was alone.
With Mom's hospital fees, Dad worked all the time and was hardly ever home.
My body is small, so people have been making fun of me since I was little.
I barely had anyone that I could call a friend.
That's why I went to the mountain by myself and looked up to the stars on the turtle rock.
But I was never lonely!
Because you were always by my side, Lion-san.
But...
This time, I'll really be alone.
Hey, Lion-san!
You still can't forget Suzunari-sensei, right?
That's why you can't leave this town, right?
Wh-What are you saying all of a sudden?
I already know.
I'm not going to be a child forever.
What are you saying, you crybaby?
I'm not a crybaby!
Then don't cry when you get to Tokyo, all right?
I won't cry!
Don't cry because you're homesick!
I said I won't cry!
Don't cry, okay?
Don't you dare cry!
Don't cry! Do your best!
Hey Kamo-san, isn't your daughter leaving today?
You don't have to bid farewell to her?
Oh, no. It's all right.
Get off at Shinjuku from the 3rd exit and ride the subway
Transit Guide Map
Tokyo
Shinjuku
Umm, the second line...
There!
Oh, I'm getting on!
Next is Shinjuku. Shinjuku.
I have to change lines.
Oh no!
Um, I'm getting off!
I went the long way around...
If I don't hurry, it'll be night.
Turn left at the second traffic light...
Turn right when you see a convenience store...
Straight ahead after the next corner...
I'm here!
Tokyo National Space School
Seagull Girls Dormitory
Excuse me!
A newcomer?
Um, y-yes.
Be quiet in the hallway!
You must have been surprised by this old dormitory.
No, not at all.
It's all right.
I mean, this place is known as the poor man's dormitory.
Now, come on in.
Oh, the shoes go there.
Just put them wherever there's an opening.
Yes.
I'll hold the trunk for you.
It's all right.
It's okay.
At this rate, you'll start making holes in these old steps.
Sorry...
Most of the kids that go to the space school are rich, right?
Nowadays there aren't many girls who want to stay in a forty-year-old dormitory in this shape.
Half the place is empty.
You're the first one to come here in two years.
This is your room.
Your things came in yesterday, so I put them in here.
Um, thank you very much.
Asumi-chan's a really nice name.
The kitchen and the washing machine on the first floor are shared.
Okay.
Well, I've got to get going to my part-time job.
Excuse me.
Huh?
Umm...
Oh, me?
Medical course, third year, Sakashita Ringo's the name.
If there's something you don't know, just ask me.
I'm like the owner of this place.
Yes, nice to meet you.
Oh, that's right.
"When you get there, open this..."
What is it?
Hot!
Itadakimasu.
Salty...
Tokyo National Space School
10th Entrance Ceremony
Asumi!
Kei-chan!
What a relief! You got in as well!
I was worried because I forgot to ask for your number.
Give me your number and your e-mail address.
Um, I don't have anything like that...
Even grade schoolers use them nowadays.
You should ask your parents to buy you one for getting into the school.
This is bad!
Let's go! The entrance ceremony is starting!
Sign: Entrance Ceremony
There sure are a lot of people when the whole school's here.
Well then, we'd better look for an empty seat.
Hey, you're really cute!
I'm having an acceptance party at my house today. Wanna come?
Please come, it'll definitely be fun!
What's going on there?
Come on, you're free today aren't you?
How about I get my driver to take you there?
Yeah, yeah!
You guys are annoying.
If you touch me with those dirty hands, I'll kill you.
Wh-What's with this girl?
Let's go.
Well, isn't she so lady-like.
We will now commence the tenth entrance ceremony of the National Tokyo Space School.
Your continuous hard work will become a cornerstone of space development.
Especially in the astronaut training course...
...that has been introduced this year.
Ah, I'm so sleepy...
I wonder what happened to that irresponsible eyebrow-less guy...
Could he have failed?
That is all!
It was a miracle for that moron, though.
Now, there will be a speech from our new student representative.
New student representative of the astronaut training course, Suzuki Shuu-kun.
Oh, he got in.
Then he must have gotten the highest grade on the entrance exam, huh?
New student representative, Suzuki Shuu-kun?
Suzuki-kun?
Suzuki Shuu-kun?
Yes, I'm here.
It looks like that guy was sleeping again.
If that's the top scorer, maybe this school isn't such a big deal.
That person...
You know him?
Yeah, well, I don't really know him...
The reason why I came to this school isn't to make stupid friends...
...nor is it get good grades to please the teachers.
I have no intention of doing that.
I only have one desire...
That's all!
Stay silent!
Everyone stay silent!
Lecture Room
In the tenth year since the construction of this school...
...we have been able to establish an astronaut training course.
That is all of you here right now.
The lecture subject is based on credits.
Plan things out to get 100 credits over the year, including the core subjects.
As for these practicals, you must clear all of them...
...or you won't be able to graduate. So be prepared.
Please turn in your schedule to the office by next week.
Hey, Asumi. For filling this in, is this place all right?
No, that would be here.
Everything was going well.
If he wasn't there...
Space Association
Ah, it's finally over.
He seemed like a really nice teacher.
What? I didn't have time to think about that!
I was getting dizzy from explanation after explanation.
Space Physics, Space Engineering...
Astronomy, Physical Geography...
Material Engineering, Heavy Industry Engineering...
Ah, geez!
It's not like we'll be doing it all at once...
It's her again.
Ukita-san!
I'm really glad that the three of us could meet together again.
Kamogawa-san.
I told you before.
I hate people who are friendly.
Huh?
You...
You're the one who was surrounded by boys and being all conceited!
Kei-chan!
Jealous?
It's unsightly.
Ah, how pathetic.
What do the guys in our school see in a girl like this?
Anyway, is your tooth cavity fixed?
How do you know that I had a tooth cavity?
Hey!
Kei-chan, your teeth hurt when they decreased the air pressure during the exam, right?
So...
If you're seriously aiming for space...
...you should worry about that more than guys.
Asumi, I'm going out to eat with my family now.
I'm going home ahead of you!
Kei-chan!
Um...
Why don't you hurry on home?
Your family's waiting, aren't they?
I'm alone even if I go home.
Hey.
Dad!
You came to my entrance ceremony!
Just a bit at the end, though.
More importantly, you still haven't eaten, right?
Want to came with me?
Yeah.
Hmm, that's strange...
I was sure it was around here...
It's been 20 years...
I'm fine with anything...
You don't have to make it luxurious just because it was my entrance ceremony...
Oh, no.
It's a restaurant she liked.
But it seems like it dosed down.
Ramen
I was planning on giving this to you today.
This is a present I got from your mother when I was still a rocket engineer.
I think you should use it from now on.
Hey, Asumi.
It might be hard, being in a place you're not used to...
...and you're still fifteen, so you must be anxious.
But never look behind you.
You won't find your dream in Yuigahama.
Oops, the ramen noodles have gone limp.
It's gotten pretty late.
Don't you dare cry.
I won't cry!
Welcome back, Asumi.
You're late! Where did you wander off to?
Don't make us worry so much!
Huh?
There's someone worried about you still running around looking...
...because you still weren't home.
Well... what was his name?
He had an odd name, black-rimmed glasses, and spiky hair in the back.
Anyway, that guy looked up my number and called me.
I had no choice but to call her too.
Try putting yourself in the place of someone forced to do this.
You say that, but weren't you looking around pretty desperately?
It wasn't like I was being desperate.
You say that, but you were worried about her, right?
Would you not contradict me every time?
Why don't you be a little more honest?
Don't you agree, Asumi?
Asumi?
What's wrong, Asumi?
Asumi!
Lion-san, I'm not crying.
I'm really happy.
It looks like I'm not alone.
National Tokyo Space School
Seagull Girls Dormitory
Ringo-san, good morning!
Hey!
I'm going now!
Lion-san, I'll do my best!
In this town!
Look up at the stars in the night
miagete goran yoru no hoshi wo
The little stars, with their little lights
chiisa na hoshi no chiisa na hikari ga
Are singing of humble happiness
sasayaka na shiawase wo utatteru
Look up at the stars in the night
miagete goran yoru no hoshi wo
Just like us, the stars without names
bokura no you ni na mo nai hoshi ga
Are praying for humble happiness
sasayaka na shiawase wo inotteru
Preview
The training that finally started was just constant running.
They say it's the first step in becoming an astronaut...
...but there seems to be quite a few classmates that are feeling anxious.
But I'll keep running, believing that everyone's longing will become reality.
Next time on Twin Spica: One Person's Dream, Everyone's Dream.﻿Dialogue: 0,0:00:03.89,0:00:07.69,OP - English,,0,0,0,,Faint-hearted traveler, you should pull back now
One Person's Dream, Everyone's Dream