Our country’s first manned exploratory space rocket, the Lion, was launched.
However, 72 seconds after liftoff…
…the liquid fuel booster suddenly exploded.
And although the Space Control Center activated what could be called its self-destruct system…
…the flight suspension system did not function correctly.
The Lion fell into an urban area and caused a huge disaster with many civilian casualties.
Five years later…
My Mother's Face
In mourning
Did you hear about Kamogawa's wife?
They said she was in that condition for five years!
It really surprised me to see her like that today.
Yuigahama Fireworks Display
Kamogawa House
It seems like it has been difficult on the father as well.
Going to work and the hospital all day...
But I really feel sorry for Asumi-chan...
She was all alone at home this whole time, right?
Ever since she could remember, she never had the chance to experience her mother’s love.
Yes. But she's a little bit of a strange child, you know.
Now then, Asumi...
Say goodbye to Mom.
Asumi!
What are you doing, Asumi?
I was wondering what she smelled like.
Smelling a dead person like that...
She's not a normal child.
Asumi, you go back to your room for a bit, okay?
Mom...
Were you always lonely?
Does it not hurt anymore?
Shoot.
It's no fair for them to fly into the sky to get away!
He's going against the good of science!
Have a good day, Dad!
Right. You be careful on your way, Asumi.
Okay.
I forgot my crayons!
Yuigahama Elementary
Family Drawings
We'll be doing art in third period.
Let’s all draw pictures of our families today!
You'll all have to clearly remember the faces of your families.
Your father, mother, siblings...
Grandmother or grandfather... Any of them are fine.
Will you be drawing your father, Asumi-chan?
Draw your family as they are, with an honest spirit.
Sensei!
Family Drawings
Yes, Fuchuuya-kun?
Kamogawa is drawing a picture of a monster!
I think that's obviously against the rules!
Huh?
What?
What is that!?
What is this thing?
It's not against the rules...
Well, then who is that?
Mom...
Huh?
So your mom is a monster, then?
But Sensei said to draw them as they are...
Ehhh?
Well then, that would make you the child of a monster, huh?
Right?
Ow!
What are you doing!?
You guys are annoying.
You little...
Hey now! Stop that!
Go for it! Don't let him say that!
Do it! Come on, don't give in!
Okay, return to your seats, everyone!
Sit down!
Dad...
What is it?
You can't sleep?
Yeah...
Where do people go when they die?
Let’s see...
According to stories that I've read in books...
...the soul becomes a spirit.
It crosses a large mountain,
heading towards a vast meadow...
...comes out of a deep forest, and beyond that forest is a big river called the Sanzu River.
NOTE: Japanese people believe the journey to the Sanzu river, the intermediate stage between life and death, takes place in 7 phases of 7 days each, or 49 days in total.
The spirit crosses the river on a boat and goes into the "other world."
Suzunari-sensei said that when people die, they become stars.
I see. Well then, Mom may become a star once she crosses the Sanzu River as well.
Now that you mention it, it's been just about 49 days now...
I wonder if Mom has crossed the Sanzu river yet.
Shoot, another drone beetle?
There aren't any stag beetles out here...
Ah, my loss for listening to what Grandpa said.
A loss in the form of three hours of wasted energy.
At 600 yen an hour, a 1800 yen loss.
I guess I'll go catch some crayfish or something.
I wonder if the Sanzu River looks sort of like this...
What is Kamogawa doing down there?
Hey!
Hey, Kamogawa!
You're totally soaked!
Hold on!
Kamogawa
There's trouble.
Mr. Kamogawa!
What's wrong, little Fuchuuya?
Kamogawa is unconscious down by the river!
What!?
Asumi!
Asumi! Asumi!
Hello? Please send an ambulance.
My daughter is in trouble!
Yes! I'm at the riverbed on the west side of Yuinogawa...
T-minus five...
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Ignition!
Liftoff!
Here.
Thank you.
Hey...
Where is this?
Well you see, this is the land of those without life.
The land of those without life...
In other words, it's a place where only dead people can come.
What? Did I die, then?
No. You're still one step on the other side.
So you need to get back to your body as quickly as possible.
How can I get back to it?
See, there's a little path running through here, right?
If you follow this path all the way
to the end, there's a big river there.
People call it the Sanzu River.
But you can't cross that river, okay?
You need to walk along that river, in the opposite direction of the flowing water.
If you do that, you can get back to your world.
Also, there's one other thing.
Those that are still living who wander into this world must never...
...say their own name aloud.
I can't say my name?
Right. Saying your own name in this place...
...means that you exist in this world, after all.
Basically, it would mean that you actually died.
Hey, you're not going to go back, onii-chan?
Let's go back together!
Unfortunately...
I don't have a body left to which I can return.
What?
Come on. If you don't get going,
everyone will be worried about you!
Little one.
Right.
Onii-chan, have I met you somewhere before?
Well, I wonder about that.
Why?
I just got that feeling...
Thank you, onii-chan.
Bye-bye.
I still haven't gotten there...
But I'm not really getting tired.
Excuse me...
I don't know who you are,
but do you suppose you could help me?
What?
Could I have you take me to the other side of the river?
I can't see, so I can't follow the path...
Are you hurt anywhere, lady?
A child?
I'll help you. Let's go!
No, it's all right.
I'm sorry.
Why are you hiding your face?
Mom...
Ah, there's a rock over there, so watch out, okay?
Over there too! And over there!
Ah, there's one over there too, okay?
Oh my! If you tell me about so many, I won't be able to walk!
But still, you re a mysterious little child, young lady.
Everyone else always gets quiet when they see me...
That's right!
I didn't hear what your name was, young lady.
Me?
I'm...
...must never say their own name aloud.
Young lady, what's wrong?
I forgot.
Is that right? That's too bad.
I'm sorry.
No, it's fine.
There's no meaning to names in this place anyway, right?
Hey...
Does your face hurt?
No. It's fine now.
But if you took off these bandages,
I'm sure you'd be very surprised.
It's very badly burned.
But my face doesn't bother me since I can't see.
You can't see anything?
No. But you know, what you see with your eyes isn't everything.
After all, I can still feel.
It seems that something sad has happened to that little girl recently.
I can feel her emotions shaking.
I have two eyes, so it would be nice if I could just give you one of them...
Then...
Then you could see the pretty sky and the pretty sea and lots and lots of other things...
Ah, that's right!
What?
Come here for a minute!
Sit down here!
What could this be?
My art homework!
I have to finish drawing my picture!
A picture of me?
Ah, don't do that! Sit still!
Right, right.
I had a little girl as well, actually.
Her name was Asumi...
I wonder how old she is now.
It would be nice if she's been raised into a kind little girl like you, young lady.
I wonder if she's doing all right.
I...
...must never say their own name.
I drew this!
You can have this picture I drew!
You're giving this to me?
Yes.
Thank you very much.
I'd like to give you something in return, but...
Then can you give me that thing you're wearing on your head?
This? It's a little dirty...
That's okay! Can I please have it?
We made it to the river!
I can see a light on the other side.
Be careful.
How are we supposed to get this boat to move, I wonder...
I'll get out and try pushing!
That's dangerous, young lady!
I'll be fine!
Wait!
I'm sorry, young lady. I'll go on ahead!
I was very happy! You were the only one who stopped and helped me!
Thank you very much!
Wait...
Fireflies?
I can see...
My eyes can see.
Asumi?
Is that you, Asumi?
I'm sorry, Mom.
I lied about forgetting my name...
I'm... Asumi.
Asumi! Don't come this way!
Mommy
You can't cross this river, Asumi!
Asumi, you keep on living!
I'm sorry, Mom.
Protecting me... It hurt a lot, didn't it?
Mom...
I, too...
You're awake, Asumi?
Really...
It's a good thing Fuchuuya-kun happened to pass by.
I... I met Mom.
Mom, you know...
She smelled really good.
What's wrong, Fuchuuya-kun?
I wasn't really looking at Kamogawa's picture!
Goodbye!
Preview
Considerate of my falling into a panic, Kei-chan wants to push the red button and retire our team.
But I want to try my best a little longer!
I want to line up dominoes with Kei-chan and Ukita-san for the rest of the time we have left!
After all, I only have one dream!
Next time on Twin Spica. Test Complete.
Test Complete