My dream!
Year 1, Class 1, Kamogawa Asumi.
My dream is to become a rocket driver!
That's because I've heard that the Earth is very
pretty when you look at it from space.
So I want to become a rocket driver and go into space!
I want to take people to all sorts of different planets!
And when they're on my rocket....
...my dad and Lion-san will get special free rides!
The end!
One Person's Dream, Everyone's Dream
I can't believe this!
In the morning, twenty laps around the track.
In the afternoon, muscle training and bike riding for an hour.
It'll be this way until graduation...
Do they intend to make us run into space?
I can't go anymore!
I'll walk...
You there. Stop being so slow!
Anyone who can't complete the laps
on time, no matter what gender...
...will run again after school!
Don't even think of being lazy!
Seriously?!
That devil...
Huh? Where's Asumi?
Asumi?
F-Fast!
Dammit!
Are you rubbing it in, you jogging dummy?
She's two laps ahead!
Now listen carefully!
After you are in a weightless environment
for a long period of time...
...your muscles and bones will get weaker
and weaker from the lack of gravity.
It's possible that when you come back down to
Earth, you won't be able to stand by yourself.
So it is important get into the habit of exercising frequently!
Before education, you need strength!
Do you understand?
Yes!
Yeah, yeah.
If you understand, ten more laps!
Ukita-san!
I have a spare, so you can use this.
Hey, the least you could do is reply.
After Asumi made the effort to...
Leave me alone!
What's she angry about?
I can't understand that girl at all.
Yeah...
More importantly, Asumi, let's hurry and have lunch!
I'm so hungry!
That instructor's a real devil!
Isn't there usually some kind of order to things?
Like starting small and going step by step...
The things we start with...
...are just messed up!
Eating or getting angry, pick one, Kei-chan.
Well, it's all right for you. You don't have to worry.
I mean, you're really fast for someone
your size. I was really surprised.
Do you do any sports?
Nothing special.
But I've been jogging every day since I was six.
Since you were six?!
Always by yourself?
Ah, yeah...
But not really by myself...
Lion-san! Wait up!
No, no. Hang on for a little longer!
I can't run any more!
Come on, take out your right leg, then your left!
Take out your right leg then your left!
I said I can't run any more!
Oh? Did you get angry, little one?
Then I'll go ahead.
Lion-san!
The crow that was crying is already laughing.
Is the rice ball that good?
Oh, not really.
More importantly, Kei-chan,
do you do any kind of exercise?
Me?
I had to do aikido up until I got into junior high.
Well, my father and grandfather are both
artisans of Japanese-style sweets...
...so they like that old-fashioned stuff.
But I'm terrible at exercising.
This is more like me.
Looking through a viewfinder like this...
Those black-rimmed glasses from last time!
Fu... Fu...
Fu-something!
Stop talking so loudly.
Fuchuuya-kun...
Eating rice balls just like always?
Because I like them!
Hey, hey, what kind of relationship do you two have?
We've been childhood friends since first grade.
Like I care about someone like this.
Which one?
He may look like this, but he's my savior.
Really?
What do you mean, "He may look like this"?
My life's been shortened because of the things you do.
Eh? Really?
Of course I'm kidding. Dummy! Dummy!
I'm not a dummy!
You're a dummy. The dummy's been chosen!
Geez, you're being mean.
I'm not being mean.
See ya!
Asumi, you're lucky.
Having a close childhood friend like that.
We're close?
I'm sure he is.
That time he was that worried about you after all.
But I used to be teased a long time ago.
What is it?
You certainly do look like you're easy to tease.
That's mean. Even you, Kei-chan?
Wait!
Oh no, we'll be late!
Let's hurry!
Astronaut Training Course
Therefore, the gravity that is placed at this point...
...can be displayed by the function of r to the power of 2.
This r is in units of the distance from the
center of the Earth to the Earth's surface.
Therefore, 6400 km is represented as 1.
In simpler words, it means that the gravity
on the Earth's surface occurs when r is 1...
...but r equals 2, so 6400 km away from the center of the Earth...
...the gravity is not one half, but one quarter of that.
This is the most important point, so please listen carefully.
The hour and a half of Space Physics sure went by quick.
Huh? You've gotta be kidding, Asumi!
Well, I was half asleep so it did in that sense.
Oh, that's right.
Where are you going, Asumi?
Kei-chan, sorry, but go ahead home!
There's something I want to ask the teacher!
She sure is enthusiastic.
Professor's Room
Sano
Yes?
U-Umm...
I'm Kamogawa.
Space Physics
There is something I wanted to ask
about the Space Physics lesson...
Umm, Sano-sensei?
I'm sorry, but I'm rather busy right now.
Would you leave it to next time?
Uh, yes. I'm sorry for causing...
Both parent and child impudently...
Tokyo National Space School
Asumi!
Kei-chan!
All done?
You were waiting for me?
Yeah, well, I was a bit worried.
You were actually worried about the notes right?
Here.
I can't possibly...
But I'll borrow it for now anyway.
See ya!
Yeah, I'll see you tomorrow!
Now Hiring Part-time
Then, we're counting on you starting tomorrow.
Yes, please take care of me.
Asumi-chan, are you there?
I thought I'd give you some of the rice that
was sent over from the countryside.
You can make a lot of your favorite rice balls...
Asumi-chan?
Huh? I thought I heard her come in a while ago...
So you were here all along.
Ah, Ringo-san.
What are you doing at a place like this?
I was making a star chart.
A star chart?
Spica
Yes, a map of the stars.
I see...
I see a different number of stars here than
back at home so I was at a loss.
So I thought I'd make the stars I see into a diagram.
This is Leo, and the one chasing it is Virgo.
It's a shame that I can only see Spica clearly from here, though.
Virgo is my favorite constellation.
In Greek mythology, it is said to be a form of the Earth goddess Demeter, who brings abundance to the lands.
The constellation bears a spear of wheat in her left hand.
The spear of wheat is right where Spica is.
That's because the word "spica" means "spear" in Latin.
And then...
Huh? What?
What's wrong?
Oh, sorry, sorry.
You looked like you were having so much fun talking...
...that I had fun listening to you too.
Oh yeah, Asumi-chan.
Have you seen the Space Resource Center already?
Space Resource Center?
Yep, it's within the school.
I thought someone like you would like it.
Thank you very much.
Space School Guide
Cafeteria
Space Resource Center
Overall Administrative Sector
Practical Sector
I see, there was something like a Space Resource Center here.
Yeah.
The school grounds here are pretty
large so I hadn't noticed it at all.
Hey, Kei-chan, why don't we take a look now?
There's still some time left until class, so...
Fuchuuya-kun too...
Why would I go, dummy?
You were there?
Not for much longer.
Asumi.
What do you want? I get it!
I'll go then, I'll go!
It's pretty big...
It's big...
Who said we'd get here quickly?
It took a long time to get here!
Let's go in, Asumi.
Okay!
Hey, wait already!
An old-fashioned H2A rocket, right?
A reduced-scale model, huh?
Yeah...
It says it's a rock sample that was brought back?!
You'd find those lying around in a NASA gift shop.
What was that?
Don't say things to shatter my dreams!
I long to go to the moon, after all.
It seems unusually noisy for a place like this.
Oh, that eyebrow-less guy that's first place!
He's just your usual sleepyhead.
That voice...
I was wondering who was there, but it's Fuchuuya-kun.
Don't call me so familiarly.
And this is? Fuchuuya-kun's friend?
I'm Suzuki Shuu.
Just call me Shuu.
Japanese people don't just walk up and shake hands.
Oh, really?
Why are you here anyway?
Why, you ask?
Just happened to be here.
You probably just went looking for
a place to sleep and ended up here.
Huh? Asumi's not here.
By Asumi, you mean...
Ah, that small girl!
I thought she was a Zashikawarashi.
NOTE: A Zashikawarashi is a fairy in the form of a little girl
who guards a house and watches over its inhabitants.
There's no way, you know!
It she's a Seagull girl, she's probably at that place.
Huh?
Where are you going?
This way, I wonder...
Wait a minute!
Really...
It's really wide open inside!
He knows the place rather well for someone
who just happened to be here.
How far are you going?
Someday, we can go to space wearing that, right?
We can all go together, right?
Space Physics
Kamogawa Asumi
Here.
Is it okay, Kei-chan? You haven't finished copying everything...
Yeah, it's okay.
I can't keep relying on other people after all.
I have to have more enthusiasm!
Kei-chan?
I want to go to space with everyone too.
Yeah.
It's that twisted woman.
Ukita-san...
Is she training by herself?
Who knows?
She must have been pretty frustrated,
not being able to keep up with you.
It's because Asumi is such a likable person.
Ah...
The first star...
Found it.
What do you want?
You know...
Ukita-san, can I call you Marika-chan?
Do as you like.
Okay!
Preview
It's time for the first grade's hiking competition.
Hiking
From the mountains I hear the harmonica of
Lion-san, whom I hadn't met in a long time.
I wander into the forest and find a rocket-shaped secret base.
Suzunari-sensei, did you know about this rocket?
Resignation
And, what is your dream, sensei?
Next time on Twin Spica: Campanella's Forest.
Campanella's Forest