Our country's first manned exploratory space rocket, the Lion, was launched.
However, 72 seconds after liftoff…
…the liquid fuel booster suddenly exploded.
And although the Space Control Center activated what could be called its self-destruct system…
…the flight suspension system did not function correctly.
The Lion fell into an urban area and caused a huge disaster with many civilian casualties.
Five years later…
Campanella's Forest
Hey, what's that?
Huh?
You're the girl from that mansion in the mountain...
What are you making?
Can't you tell by looking?
No.
It's a rocket.
A rocket-shaped secret base.
Can I come again?
I won't tell anyone about this place.
If you don't tell anyone...
It's all right.
Would you like to dance?
Hiking
Everyone, listen up!
Yuigahama Elementary School
Tomorrow is the Yuigahama Elementary
School's annual hiking competition.
The first grade will climb up the Mitake mountain you see behind the school.
The safety guidelines are written on
the sheet, so follow them properly...
Now, everyone be quiet!
Hey, be quiet!
I'm telling you to be quiet!
Anyway, listen carefully.
I hear it...
Kamogawa-san?
Where are you going?
Hey, wait, all of you too?
Return to your seats!
Staff Room
Suzunari-sensei!
What's wrong? You look so down.
Why did I think that I wanted to
be an elementary school teacher?
Did something happen?
Don't tell me you're ill.
I'm sort of losing my confidence...
Ah, that's right!
The teachers from Kitachuu are having a party this Saturday.
Won't you come with me?
You always skip these things, don't you?
There'll be nice guys there, so...
Hey.
Dad...
This is a birthday cake.
You've loved big strawberry cakes since you were a kid, right, Yuuko?
Stop treating me like a child all the time.
I'm already twenty-four now.
Twenty-four, huh?
It seems so sudden.
You used to be this tiny and were such a cry-baby...
...but now you're already twenty-four...
Yuuko...
How long are you going to fuss over this town?
What do you mean, "this town"?
You still can't forget about him?
It's not a bad thing to hold on to your feelings for another...
...but he is someone who has already died.
Isn't it time you looked toward the future?
It's been five years since the accident.
Isn't that long enough?
Come back to Tokyo.
Dad, I...
Your mother's worried about you.
To have you married and taking over our shop...
That's what your mother hopes for.
If you can, can you set your mother's mind at ease?
Forget it all...
About the accident...
About him...
Yuigahama?
Yep, the town where I was born.
It's a place where the sea and the mountains look really beautiful.
The mountains were like the kids' territory.
I even had a secret hiding place.
At bad times, or hard times. I'd go there and look at the stars.
When I'd do that. I'd mysteriously feel better.
Compared to the tens of thousands of light
years between here and the stars...
...I realized that my own troubles were very tiny things.
I can get closer to those stars soon.
My dreams are coming true!
Everyone gather!
Water of Heaven
Forest Hiking area
Now, everyone in the first grade, listen carefully.
You will now be split into groups to go together.
While you're looking for signs with bird marks, try your hardest and try to get the most.
Do not wander off by yourself under any circumstances!
Why did I end up with you, of all people?
What was that?
Now, let's start!
Found it!
Really?
Sun
Let's see, number three, the password is "sun"...
Okay!
Let's go to the next one!
Yeah!
Hey, where is it?
See, over there!
Up there!
Sun
You're right! It's there!
Hey, Asumi-chan, did you know?
What?
They said if you find all ten bird marks, you get to have a memorial medal!
That's why the boys are so enthusiastic.
What about over there?
But my brother said it was probably impossible.
We should go and look!
Only one person has ever gotten the medal he said.
I see...
Jupiter
I have found it!
You've done a good job!
Number six, the password is "Jupiter".
"Jupiter"...
All right, that's five!
Hey! You guys are too slow!
That's why girls are so...
Be quiet already!
Moon
All right! Found the ninth one!
Awesome! Just one more left!
The tenth one isn't around here anywhere...
Did I miss it?
Asumi-chan!
Asumi-chan! Let's go!
Really... what are you doing?
We'll leave you behind, Kamogawa!
I hear it...
Huh? What do you hear?
The sound of a harmonica...
Huh? Are you a dummy?
Why would you hear a harmonica
in the middle of the mountains?
I hear it! Lion-san's harmonica!
H-Hey! Where are you going?
Hey, wait up!
Asumi-chan!
Fuchuuya!
Sensei!
Suzunari-sensei!
What's the meaning of this, Suzunari-sensei?
A girl and a boy from my class went into
the woods and haven't returned...
I told you to watch the students closely!
I'm sorry.
In any case, let's split up and search for them.
It something happens, it'll be your responsibility!
Yes.
This way!
It's a rocket!
Resignation
What is this?
I've lost the confidence to continue working here.
That's very unlike you, Suzunari-sensei.
A lot of things happen when you're young.
Try and remember why you started this work in the first place.
Resignation
I'll return this to you for now.
I don't know.
I don't know what I want to do.
I'm lonely...
...and empty...
It feels like I'm being crushed...
Asumi-chan!
Fuchuuya-kun!
Help me... Takano-kun...
I miss you...
I want to see you...
Asumi-chan!
Sensei!
Fuchuuya-kun!
Where's Asumi-chan?
I lost her somewhere around here.
She's a dummy, but she runs really fast!
So which way did she go?
Let's see... that way.
Or maybe it was this way?
Huh? Maybe it was...
Which way is it?!
Even if you yell at me, I don't know! I just don't know!
Sensei, haven't you been a bit hysterical lately?
In any case, let's look for Asumi-chan.
Sensei!
There...
A railroad track?
I don't remember a train going through here...
No, this is a discontinued line.
They aren't used anymore.
Huh?
Why do I know this, when I've never been here before...
Sensei!
Which way are we going to look now?
Let's see... let's try going further into the forest.
It's like a mummy hunter turning into a mummy!
Note: A quote used when one goes out looking
for someone, but does not return.
I don't think that dummy would die easily, but...
Fuchuuya-kun!
Let's rest a bit.
I ran out?!
I'm so unlucky!
Nothing good comes from being involved with Kamogawa!
Here, I'll give you mine.
Thanks!
How did I know about this discontinued line?
There's this railroad track that isn't used...
That's right, Takano-kun was...
There's this railroad track that isn't used.
It travels straight through the forest.
I made a secret base there.
Every day I went there, untiringly taking plywood and iron plates.
A rocket-shaped secret headquarters...
That's right!
Sensei?
We're going now!
You go and take a look at the right side!
Geez, you're such a slave driver.
Found it...
Wh-What is this?
Aren't you a fool?
You know you'll get lost in a forest like this, don't you?
So why?
I heard the sound of a harmonica.
It's because I wanted to see Lion-san!
Lion-san disappeared, and I...
I was waiting and waiting!
I see, you want to see Lion-san...
But that person's already...
Ah, look at this!
It's the hiking competition memorial medal!
What's it doing here?
That was inside that treasure box.
Treasure box?
I hear it...
Hey!
Dummy! Where are you going?
"When I grow up..."
Kamogawa!
"When I grow up, I want to be an astronaut."
I want to be an astronaut...
"I want to see the same blue Earth that Gagarin saw."
"From the window of the rocket in outer space..."
"...I want to see Yuigahama and the Yuigahama fireworks that I like."
That is my...
...my dream.
Resignation
Hello? Dad?
Yeah.
I can't go back to Tokyo after all.
It's not that.
I've already sorted out my feelings about that accident.
Yeah, give my regards to Mom.
I'm really sorry.
Yuigahama Elementary School
Yoshida-sensei!
Are there really going to be nice guys at today's party?
I want to try living with lots and lots of children with the light of their dreams sparkling in their earnest eyes.
Takano-kun, that is my dream!
Earth
Ah, it was over here!
The tenth mark!
Good job finding it.
Lion-san!
You still haven't fulfilled your promise, after all.
My promise?
You're going to take me on your rocket, right?
Earth
Yeah!
Preview
It's the first time we're trying on the space suits.
But, I'm shocked because there aren't any sizes that fit me.
This is a problem, and Sano-sensei's trying to make me quit...
On the other hand, Marika-chan is still stubborn,
and is always fighting with Kei-chan...
...even though no one can go to space by themselves.
Next time on Twin Spica: Even Underwater, There Is Space.
Even Underwater, There Is Space