My dream!
Year 1, Class 1, Kamogawa Asumi.
My dream is to become a rocket driver!
That's because I've heard that the Earth is very pretty when you look at it from space.
So I want to become a rocket driver and go into space!
I want to take people to all sorts of different planets!
And when they're on my rocket...
...my dad and Lion-san will get special free rides!
The end!
Asumi's Dream
Tokyo Space School Entrance Exam Session
Exam No.
Tokyo Space Academy Exam
Astronaut Training Course
Examinee Number
Kamogawa Asumi
That's it!
I'll collect your examination papers here.
There will be a logic test in the afternoon, so make sure to be here an hour early.
Mercury, Venus...
Earth, Mars, Jupiter...
Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, Pluto...
Kamogawa.
KAMOGAWA.
KAMOGAWA!
Yes!
What were you looking at instead of paying attention to class?
Um, the stars. I was looking at the stars.
In broad daylight!?
That again?
Kamogawa, make sure to come to the teachers' office after class.
Teacher's Office
I'm very sorry.
Kamogawa-san?
Ah, yes?
Do you have some time right now?
Future Questionnaire
For this...
Ah, Kamogawa-san!
You're on cleanup duty, right?
Ah, was I?
We're all done with our part...
...so take care of the rest, okay?
Since you're always causing us so much trouble...
...that much shouldn't be a big deal, right?
Of course it isn't.
Now then, let's go home!
Hey, you wanna grab some tea first?
I do!
Ah, I'll go too!
Fuchuuya-kun!
Why are you letting them push all of this on you?
Well, but I'm the one at fault.
You need to do things more clearly, you know?
If you don't, it's easy to be misunderstood.
It bothers me when I see that!
You know...
Where are you trying for?
Are you really...
What?
Eh. Nevermind, it's nothing.
Yuigahama Station
1961, the USSR sends up the first manned space flight.
1969, Apollo 11 completes man's first landing on the moon's surface.
Yuigahama Station
And also Japan's...
Police Box
Even studying on the train...
Very impressive.
Geez!
You stupid lion! Pervert!
That's not it!
That is it!
What is that girl making a fuss over all alone?
That wasn't it!
Wait!
I can't let you catch me!
Yeah...
I can't let you catch me.
You little...!
That wasn't it, really!
See, look at this!
So you still want to go after all, don't you?
To space school?
Lion-san, you used to be an astronaut, right?
Were the exams really a lot of work?
It wasn't just a lot of work.
In Japan back then, they had just started training astronauts.
Of course, there was no Space Academy...
You would never even think of being an astronaut when you were just a teenager.
Day-to-day life hasn't changed much...
...but I guess that just shows how much closer space has gotten for us.
Although if that accident hadn't happened,
it would have been quicker...
More importantly, will it be okay, little one?
Huh?
You still haven't talked with your father about it, have you?
Telling him you want to go to the Space Academy in Tokyo...
Right...
I'm back!
Welcome home, Dad!
Really, that old man.
Working us so hard, this late into the night.
Dinner’s ready, okay?
It's just curry though, right?
This is the third straight day!
Well, with our finances in this state...
I can't compla—
Are you all right, Dad?
M-My back just suddenly... Ow, ow!
It would be nice if we had an electric massager, wouldn't it?
Don't be silly.
Where would we get that kind of money?
That's true, but...
You're perfect.
Huh?
Your weight.
You're just the right weight for me.
Hey, are you serious about this, Kamogawa-san?
Guidance Counseling Room
For relatives of applicants
Tokyo National Space School
Admissions Application Requirements
Well, it's not that I can't understand
the desire to be an astronaut, but...
The astronaut training course was just established...
...so you’d be one of the first to go through it.
I think it would be a lot of work for a girl.
You're the smallest girl in the school, anyway.
The tuition for a national school like
this can be pretty overwhelming.
Besides, how do you plan to attend that school when you live all the way out here?
It says that there's a dorm for applicants.
Kamogawa-san, I seem to remember...
Your mother passed away when you were young...
...and you're living alone with your father right now, aren't you?
Yes.
If you end up attending this school...
...you'll be leaving your father all alone, won't you?
Your father wasn't against this idea or anything?
Huh?
My father...
He didn't really...
Good morning, Dad!
He's not here...
Really, he's such a slob!
work schedule
early shift normal shift late shift
Oh, he's on the early shift.
I guess he really wouldn't be able to do without me here...
At this rate...
My dream!
Year 1, Class 1, Kamogawa Asumi.
My dream is to become a rocket driver and take people to all sorts of different planets!
Moron! You don't say a rocket "driver!"
It's a pilot!
Asumi, do your best!
Now, father, please be quiet.
And my dad and Lion-san will get special free rides!
Your composition at school was very well done.
Yeah!
Um...
Thanks for everything, Dad!
Here, you can have this!
Hm, what's this?
A present!
Dad!
It's so big!
Asumi...
Mom is up there too, isn't she?
Let’s go see her together on my rocket!
Yeah, let's. Someday...
Promise!
Right, it's a promise!
If I tell a lie, make me swallow a thousand needles!
Dad says that he actually used to be pretty cool and popular.
Of course, he's talking about himself, so you can't be too sure about it.
Huh...
When I was little, he always wore a business suit.
He was a rocket engineer, after all.
But now he's such a slob, and sort of insensitive...
...and he always looks tired, so he seems pretty unreliable.
Little one, look.
Orion...
In the middle of all those stars, the alpha star, Betelgeuse.
Even though it looks so small...
...it's actually a huge star, more than 500 times the size of the sun.
It's called a supergiant.
If we don't think much about it,
we would never realize how big the star is.
As long as we can't see it with our own eyes...
...we can't tell how brightly it shines.
It's the same way with people.
I'm home!
Ah, you're home early today!
I'll get dinner ready right now.
What are you doing in here without the lights on?
For relatives of applicants
Tokyo National Space School
Admissions Application Requirements
I got a call from your homeroom teacher.
What does this mean?
Oh, geez! Don't go looking at my stuff!
I'm asking you what this means.
It's nothing, really...
Besides, this doesn't really matter anymore. Let's have dinner.
What do you mean, it doesn't matter?
Th-That hurts, Dad! Let go of me!
Say it clearly, Asumi. Why doesn't it matter?
I told you, it's nothing, really.
I just thought I would take it for memory's sake.
I thought I would see if I could pass it!
Even if I passed, we don't have the money to pay for it...
And I wasn't really thinking of leaving you here alone and going off to Tokyo!
I wasn't asking you about any of that.
Account Book
I'll be coming home late from now on.
I won't need dinner.
Yuigahama Middle School
This sums up all of this year, so make sure to remember it...
Safety first
Kamogawa
Dad!
work schedule
early shift normal shift late shift
There...
Note: Listing of High Schools
Little one!
Are you giving up on space school?
Lion-san, I don't know what I should do anymore.
Dad hasn't said much to me since then...
...and he works day and night, only coming home to sleep.
But of course, Dad is mad at me...
After all, we don't have the money for that...
...and Dad would be all alone.
And Mom...
But, I...
Hey, little one...
Your father isn't mad at you because you
went and took the exam on your own.
It wasn't because you didn't tell him about it, either.
What your dad couldn't stand...
...was probably seeing you unable to honestly talk about your dreams anymore, little one.
I want to become a rocket driver!
I wasn't asking you about any of that.
…was probably seeing you unable to honestly talk about your dreams anymore, little one.
Snow?
Safety first
If we don't think much about it, we would never realize how big the star is.
As long as we can't see it with our own eyes...
...we can't tell how brightly it shines.
You'll freeze sitting down out here.
Heh! Don't treat me like an old man!
Umm...
Dad, I...
Wait, I know.
Here.
This...
That's my entire savings.
That should be enough for it, right?
I've asked them to give me more work, so we should be able to take care of the school fees somehow.
Dad...
Listen, Asumi.
Children shouldn't have to be hesitant around their parents.
Besides, the two of us only have each other as family.
You're my one and only daughter.
Hey, Asumi...
If it would help you on your way to happiness,
I don't care what happens to my body.
I wouldn't mind selling our household goods, the whiskey, the house, or our land.
I have this, after all.
This thing that you gave to me when you were little, Asumi.
As long as I have this...
Dad, um... Thank you for everything!
Here, you can have this!
A present!
For Dad:
Pass for free rides on Asumi's rocket
Rocket Asumi Dad
Asumi, your dream is my most important treasure.
Tokyo National Space School
Entrance Exam Conference Room
Interview Room
Number 95, Kamogawa Asumi-san.
Yes!
Kamogawa-san, why is it that you want to attend this school?
Well, I...
Becoming an astronaut has been a dream of mine ever since I was a child!
So being admitted to this school would be one step in changing that dream into reality.
If I'm admitted, in order to become an astronaut...
For Lion-san:
Pass for free rides on Asumi's rocket
Lion-san
Asumi
Preview
The admissions test for space school is over!
Or so I thought, but everyone who passed has to take a secondary exam!
An exam where you have to spend a whole week with a group of three people in one small room!
In the same room as me, there are two girls who are completely different types.
What in the world is the objective of this test?
Next time on Twin Spica: One Step Toward the Stars.
One Step Toward the Stars